<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Hector Ramos</title>
 <link href="http://hectorramos.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://hectorramos.com/"/>
 <updated>2011-07-13T18:42:08-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://hectorramos.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Héctor ramos</name>
   <email>hi@hectorramos.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Netflix Streaming works in Puerto Rico</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/netflix-instant-watch-works-in-puerto-rico"/>
   <updated>2011-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/netflix-instant-watch-works-in-puerto-rico</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/399px-Netflix_Logo.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The time is finally here: Netflix Watch Instantly, the video streaming service, is now available in Puerto Rico. One of the very first posts in this website was regarding the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hectorramos.com/netflix-excludes-puerto-rico-charges&quot; title=&quot;Netflix excludes Puerto Rico, charges full price&quot;&gt;unavailability of Netflix in Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;, as you may remember. We can now put that issue to rest, as Netflix sent out an email to all of its Puerto Rico customers, announcing the fact that Watch Instantly is now available again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://edgarrodriguez.com/netflix-says-that-instant-watch-woks-on-my-ar&quot; title=&quot;Netflix email by Edgar Rodriguez&quot;&gt;Edgar Rodriguez&lt;/a&gt; for letting us know about the email. No longer being a Netflix customer, as I had cancelled my service in 2009 when they blocked Watch Instantly in Puerto Rico, I didn't receive the email. I don't know what led to Netflix reenabling Watch Instantly - I had already given up on them. I know many people cancelled their accounts, but many more just used proxies, VPNs and other workarounds, judging by all the comments and emails I have received over the last two years. Personally, I believe that any company that makes it hard for me to use the service I am paying for, does not deserve my money. So I cancelled my service instead of jumping through hoops to get it working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the most simple explanation is that Netflix finally got it all sorted out. Hulu Plus, iTunes Rentals and Xbox Video Rentals already work in Puerto Rico, with pretty much the same VOD catalog, so why would Netflix be any different? Well, they do have a physical DVD rental service, with its own availability windows. If their licensing contracts for streaming were somewhat tied to the physical rental licensing they already had in place, it is not too much of a longshot to theorize that Netflix couldn't just switch over from one day to the next and have all contracts in place. Just this past weekend, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.turntable.fm&quot; title=&quot;Turntable&quot;&gt;Turntable.fm&lt;/a&gt; blocked International users and Puerto Rico was caught in the block, even if for a couple of hours. Even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2F%23&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot; title=&quot;Amazon&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; places various restrictions on the goods they can ship to Puerto Rico, although we are eligible for their Super Saver free shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as we would like everybody to treat us like the United States territory that we are, the fact of the matter is that we are a nation stuck in limbo: not fully a State, not fully a sovereign nation. Until we get that sorted out, we can only expect more misunderstandings and different interpretations of copyright, trademark and cabotage laws.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Objectify. Give JSON, Receive Code.</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/objectify"/>
   <updated>2011-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/objectify</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been testing &lt;a href=&quot;http://tigerbears.com/objectify/&quot;&gt;Objectify&lt;/a&gt; for the last few weeks, and I'm happy to see it &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/objectify/id435651677&quot;&gt;available now on the Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cl.ly/71b4/content.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/71b4/content.png&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height=&quot;251&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objectify is an indispensable addition to an Objective-C programmer's toolbelt. It's pretty simple, actually: feed it some JSON, and it will spit out a set of classes all ready to handle that &lt;a href=&quot;http://json.org&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt;. Be it for quick prototyping, or for actual use in your app, this effectively saves you all the time it would take you to wire up your base classes. It's simple but tedious work that can now be taken care of with a few clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objectify has quickly found a spot in my development routine. For example, I used Objectify last night to write a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wufoo.com&quot;&gt;Wufoo forms&lt;/a&gt; wrapper in 20 minutes using the documentation's sample JSON payloads. I am also using it in an upcoming app that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polsense.com&quot; title=&quot;Polsense - iOS Development&quot;&gt;Polsense&lt;/a&gt; is working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get Objectify today on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/objectify/id435651677&quot;&gt;MAS&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://tigerbears.com/objectify/&quot; title=&quot;Objectify iOS JSON wrangler&quot;&gt;buy it&lt;/a&gt; directly from  &lt;a href=&quot;http://tigerbears.com&quot;&gt;tigerbears&lt;/a&gt;. You may also Objectify updates on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/objectifyapp&quot;&gt;@objectifyapp&lt;/a&gt;. Congrats to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/billkunz&quot;&gt;Bill Kunz&lt;/a&gt; for shipping this great app!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>May Update</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/may-update"/>
   <updated>2011-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/may-update</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two big releases this week. Liberty Cablevision has launched their new iPhone app, which was &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.polsense.com/liberty-cable-iphone-application&quot; title=&quot;Liberty Cable iPhone Application&quot;&gt;developed in partnership with Polsense&lt;/a&gt;. I'm really proud of what we've done with this app, from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've also been working nights and weekends on another app that saw the light this week: EyeTour. From the makers of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eyetour.com/&quot; title=&quot;EyeTour&quot;&gt;Puerto Rico's premier video guide&lt;/a&gt;, the EyeTour iPhone app helps you &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/eyetour/id414703689&quot; title=&quot;EyeTour iPhone app&quot;&gt;explore the island of Puerto Rico on the go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both projects have been a huge part of my life for the last year. I hope you enjoy them. There's more coming real soon. Polsense has been working on another iOS application for the last six weeks, but we are not ready to say more at the moment. I'm also working on another iOS app, which reminds me: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedxsanjuan.com&quot; title=&quot;TEDxSanJuan&quot;&gt;TEDxSanJuan&lt;/a&gt; will take place this Fall. We're working on getting the final website up and running, but until then, &lt;a href=&quot;http://clearshore.wufoo.com/forms/nominate-a-speaker-tedxsanjuan-19-nov-2011/&quot; title=&quot;Nominate a Speaker for TEDxSanJuan&quot;&gt;TEDxSanJuan Speaker Nominations ARE OPEN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SXSW 2011</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-2011"/>
   <updated>2011-03-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I’m leaving in a few hours for SXSW. I’ve been looking forward to visiting Austin again, seeing friends and meeting in person everyone I’ve been interacting with online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you’re going to be in Austin this weekend for SXSW!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I’ve been working on a new blog based on Jekyll. It’s almost done, but I don’t think it would be prudent to deploy it just before leaving for this trip. So that explains the lack of blogging - I keep telling myself I should wait until the new site is up!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Automating iOS Over The Air Beta Deployment</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/automating-ios-over-air-beta-deployment"/>
   <updated>2011-01-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/automating-ios-over-air-beta-deployment</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A nifty feature introduced in iOS 4.0 was Over The Air binary deployments. You can use these to distribute your Ad Hoc beta app without having your users deal with iTunes and mobile provisioning profiles. It&amp;#8217;s a great time saver and much friendlier to use than the previous tethered method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating these OTA deployments used to be very tedious. I&amp;#8217;ve been learning Rails this past week, and really liked the way Heroku allows you to git push to their servers to deploy. Last night, I wrote up some scripts to simulate this as close as possible. I&amp;#8217;ll first go through the basics of OTA deployments, the meaty automation action is at the last section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Over The Air Deployment Basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to skip this section if you&amp;#8217;ve been doing OTA deployments already. Automation details are further down the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way this works is through the use of a manifest file and a specially formatted iTunes URL. An example manifest is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/774468.js?file=manifest.plist&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is a standard ASCII plist &amp;#8212; you may use the OS X Property List Editor, or launch your favorite text editor and copy/paste this into a new file. Change the ${###} values to whatever matches your application; use your own Info.plist as a guide for the bundle id, display name and version number, and choose a URL that matches the final public URL where your app will be available to beta testers. For example, you might own the http://google.com domain, so you&amp;#8217;d decide to host future betas of the Google +1 iOS apps at http://beta.google.com/plusone/GooglePlusOne.ipa. This must be a directory that is open to the Internet, as your iOS device must be able to download the IPA file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manifest and IPA files are linked to from any web page of your own choosing. Just use the following URL format when doing so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/774499.js?file=_manifest-link.html&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a full HTML file that you may use if you don&amp;#8217;t have a mobile formatted web page just yet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/774481.js?file=index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Just replace the Google +1 dummy data with your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the beta_archive.zip link? That&amp;#8217;s what we serve to Pre-iOS 4.0 users, since OTA is a 4.0 feature. This is a zip containing the IPA and mobile provision necessary for classic iTunes tethered installs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve done all of this, you don&amp;#8217;t need to recreate these files unless the application version number, bundle id or display name change (they must match the values in your Info.plist file).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But Wait&amp;#8230; How Do I Create an IPA?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build and Archive an ad hoc distribution target. Won&amp;#8217;t go into details, just make sure to use a development Ad Hoc distribution provisioning profile. I recommend creating a new Target just for these Ad Hoc deployments. This way you don&amp;#8217;t have to change the Code Signing settings every time, plus it will allow you to run this build from the command line &amp;#8212; the end goal is to automate this process, remember?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a screen cap from one of my apps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c0185824.cdn1.cloudfiles.rackspacecloud.com/2011-01-code_signing.png&quot; alt=&quot;Code Signing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No code signing entitlements, just a distribution provisioning profile that was created for Ad Hoc deployments in Apple&amp;#8217;s iOS Provisioning Portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;#8217;s set, just make sure your Ad Hoc target is active and then select Device (as opposed to Simulator) from your Xcode drop down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c0185824.cdn1.cloudfiles.rackspacecloud.com/2011-01-device.png&quot; alt=&quot;Xcode Dropdown Device&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Build and select Build and Archive (if it&amp;#8217;s gray, go back to the previous step and SELECT DEVICE, not Simulator):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c0185824.cdn1.cloudfiles.rackspacecloud.com/2011-01-build.png&quot; alt=&quot;Build&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c0185824.cdn1.cloudfiles.rackspacecloud.com/2011-01-comlink.png&quot; alt=&quot;COM:LINK&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of minutes, the Xcode Organizer will pop up. Search for your application under Archived Applications, and then select the latest archive. Feel free to assign it a name that is useful to you &amp;#8212; in my case, I use the same git tag that was applied to this code before being pushed. Once that&amp;#8217;s out of the way, select your archive and then click on Share. Select the same Ad Hoc provisioning profile that you used during the build, then save it to disk. This will generate the IPA file that you need for OTA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Do I Really Need To Do All Of This Myself?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, yes, you need to Build and Archive, but you can then use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hanchorllc.com/2010/08/24/introducing-ios-beta-builder/&quot;&gt;iOS Beta Builder&lt;/a&gt; to create the manifest and HTML files necessary for OTA deployment. Yes, this is what I used to generate the above files. I could have told you initially, but then we wouldn&amp;#8217;t learn anything new, would we? iOS Beta Builder is what I&amp;#8217;ve been using for OTA deployments since last summer, and it works very well. It will generate all your files, after which you can just zip them up, upload to your website and extract them to their final location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Enter Testflight&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option, which I highly recommend, is to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://testflightapp.com&quot;&gt;Testflight&lt;/a&gt;. These guys have been working hard for months on creating the most painless way to distribute your beta deployments over the air. All you need to do is supply the IPA file, select your team members (use their email addresses) and they will receive a nice, mobile formatted email with the link to your IPA file. The link opens Safari, from where they can click on Install and &amp;#8212; well, that&amp;#8217;s it! The app is now installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c0185824.cdn1.cloudfiles.rackspacecloud.com/2011-01-testflightapp.png&quot; alt=&quot;Testflight&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testflight has other nifty features. You may manage multiple teams within each of your application. Say, you have one or two other developers and designers working on your app, you may choose to send them all of the daily builds. You may have another team for the client and just send them the end of week progress builds. And the most important feature, whenever you add a new team member, they get an email where with one or two clicks they can get their UDID registered with Testflight, saving you the need to explain them how to extract it themselves. Testflight also provides a way to batch download all the UDIDs which you can then upload to Apple&amp;#8217;s iOS Provisioning Portal and add to your Ad Hoc distribution profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testflight really requires its own standalone review to do it justice. They are in closed beta at the moment (although they opened up their sign up during the holidays!). Wait for them to go public, contact them, or follow them on Twitter to snag your signup next time they open up again. Oh, and being invited to a Testflight team also gives you your own account, so that also works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point goes to Testflight for providing an &lt;a href=&quot;http://testflightapp.com/api/doc/&quot;&gt;upload API&lt;/a&gt;, which is really useful for &amp;#8212; you guessed it &amp;#8212; over the air deployment automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alright! Just Tell Me How To Automate All Of This Crap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you need to do two things: automate your Xcode build, and then automate the IPA upload to your web server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part is taken care of by the following script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/774017.js?file=buildandarchive.sh&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Change all the variables to match your own development environment. The end result, if successful, is the IPA file you need and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may now create a simple script that scp&amp;#8217;s the IPA to its final location in your web server, alongside the manifest.plist and index.html previously created with iOS Beta Builder. You should be able to do this easily, if not, then Google&amp;#8217;s your best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, thanks to Testflight, you can just call this script once the Xcode build has been successful. It will &lt;a href=&quot;http://testflightapp.com/api/doc/&quot;&gt;upload the IPA to Testflight&lt;/a&gt; and automatically email your team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/773985.js?file=upload-testflight.sh&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The team token determines which of your teams, within your Testflight configured apps, receives this deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you&amp;#8217;re an awesome code monkey, it shouldn&amp;#8217;t be too hard to link these two scripts together so that the Archive name and comments are kept consistent with the Testflight notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current deployment set up is an alias that first calls &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;, and if successful, calls the build and archive script, which then in turn calls the Testflight deployment script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it out, and let me know if this works out for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quick iPhone 4 HDR Samples</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/hdr-samples"/>
   <updated>2011-01-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/hdr-samples</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On New Year&amp;#8217;s Day, Addis and I took a road trip to the southwestern corner of the island. We visited the seaside cliffs of Cabo Rojo&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/spots/305070&quot;&gt;Los Morrillos&lt;/a&gt; lighthouse, where I snapped the following picture with my iPhone 4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 4 has a software HDR function which takes various pictures in quick succession, each with varying exposure levels, and merges them into a single composite which should have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High_dynamic_range_imaging&quot;&gt;higher dynamic range&lt;/a&gt; of colors (which your monitor probably can&amp;#8217;t display properly, but done right, still looks better than a single exposure picture, but I won&amp;#8217;t go into the details). The iPhone 4 also saves the original, single exposure picture in case you prefer it over the HDR.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hramos/5326925333/&quot; title=&quot;No HDR by Hector Ramos, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5002/5326925333_cd0807c1c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;No HDR&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hramos/5326925333/&quot; title=&quot;No HDR by Hector Ramos, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5002/5326925333_cd0807c1c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;No HDR&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can you spot the difference?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-2220337725572652372?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Drop In Reachability Check</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/drop-in-reachability-check"/>
   <updated>2010-12-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/drop-in-reachability-check</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every iOS application that requires an Internet connection should make use of the Apple &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/library/ios/#samplecode/Reachability/Introduction/Intro.html&quot;&gt;Reachability&lt;/a&gt; classes. These allow you to easily check if there is a WAN connection available and/or if a specific host can be reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You never know when your application will run in Airport mode or in a dead area with no cell connection at all. Furthermore, the user might not have 3G service but might be connected through a Wi-Fi hotspot. Perhaps in a future OS update, an additional WAN connection might become available through Bluetooth or a completely new protocol. For these reasons, I can&amp;#8217;t advise you to create your own Reachability code, when Apple&amp;#8217;s will suffice: you only care if there is access to a WAN, or at the very least, if Host X is reachable (who cares about the pathway to it?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iPhone OS 2, the Reachability classes were kind of obscure, hidden away in the Apple Sample Code and with no easy way of dropping them in to a project. By default they were synchronous and would need some modification to work properly asynchronously - I don&amp;#8217;t really remember the details, I just remember I had to do this a couple of times and it was very annoying. So I was very happy to find &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1083701/how-to-check-for-an-active-internet-connection-on-iphone-sdk/3597085#3597085&quot;&gt;this answer in Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; which provides a step by step to use the updated Reachability classes along with NSNotifications to asynchronously determine reachability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should always &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1083701/how-to-check-for-an-active-internet-connection-on-iphone-sdk/3597085#3597085&quot;&gt;visit Stack Overflow to get the latest code and comments&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;#8217;m saving a local copy here for posterity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An updated answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Add &lt;code&gt;SystemConfiguration&lt;/code&gt; framework to the project but don&amp;#8217;t worry about including it anywhere&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Add &lt;code&gt;Reachability.h&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Reachability.m&lt;/code&gt; to the project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Add &lt;code&gt;@class Reachability;&lt;/code&gt; to the .h file of where you are implementing the code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Create a couple instances to check in the &lt;code&gt;interface&lt;/code&gt; section of the .h file:
Liquid error: No such file or directory - pygmentize -l objectivec -f html -O encoding=utf-8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Add a method in the .h for when the network status updates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liquid error: No such file or directory - pygmentize -l objectivec -f html -O encoding=utf-8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Add &lt;code&gt;#import &quot;Reachability.h&quot;&lt;/code&gt; to the .m file where you are implementing the check&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) In the .m file of where you are implementing the check, you can place this in one of the first methods called (&lt;code&gt;
init&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;viewWillAppear&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;viewDidLoad&lt;/code&gt;, etc.):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liquid error: No such file or directory - pygmentize -l objectivec -f html -O encoding=utf-8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Set up the method for when the notification gets sent and set whatever checks or call whatever methods you may have set up (in my case, I just set a BOOL)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liquid error: No such file or directory - pygmentize -l objectivec -f html -O encoding=utf-8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) In your &lt;code&gt;dealloc&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;viewWillDisappear&lt;/code&gt; or similar method, remove yourself as an observer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liquid error: No such file or directory - pygmentize -l objectivec -f html -O encoding=utf-8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: There might be an instance using &lt;code&gt;viewWillDisappear&lt;/code&gt; where you receive a memory warning and the observer never gets unregistered so you should account for that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Did I ever tell you about Ashton?</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/did-i-ever-tell-you-about-ashton"/>
   <updated>2010-12-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/did-i-ever-tell-you-about-ashton</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ashton was your classic corn-fed farm boy. His parents had been hippies who never really managed to get their acts together until his mother inherited 15 acres in a rural part of Michigan. The family moved out there, bought a couple of dairy goats, and struggled to make a living selling organic goat cheese to the yuppies at the Ann Arbor Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the time he was ten years old, Ashton had to wake up every morning at 4:00 a.m. and milk those damn goats, and it was exhausting. Ashton loved going to school because it meant he wasn&amp;rsquo;t working knee-deep in goat poop. Throughout high school, he studied his ass off, hoping that a scholarship to a good university would be his ticket out of the farm. He found college to be so much easier than farm life that he didn&amp;rsquo;t understand why everyone else didn&amp;rsquo;t get straight A&amp;rsquo;s like him. He majored in Software Engineering because he couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine engineers ever being required to wake up at 4:00 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ashton graduated from school without knowing much about the software industry, really, so he went to the career fair, applied for three jobs, got accepted by all three, and picked the one that paid the most: something insane like $32,000 a year, working at a big furniture company in the southwestern part of the state that manufactured cubicle farms for corporations all over the world. He never wanted to see a farm again, so he was determined to make a good impression on his boss, Charlie Sherman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s not going to be easy,&amp;rdquo; his cubicle-mate, Jeff, said. &amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;s something of a legend here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you mean?&amp;rdquo; he asked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you remember a few years ago, when there was all that uproar about Y2K?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ashton was probably too young. &amp;ldquo;Y2K?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know, nobody expected that all the old computer programs written in the 1960s would still be running in 2000, so they only had room for two digits for the year. Instead of storing 1999, they would store 99. And then when the year flipped over on January 1st, 2000, the computer systems crashed, because they tried to fit &amp;ldquo;100&amp;rdquo; in two digits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Really? I thought that was a myth,&amp;rdquo; Ashton said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At every other company in the world, nothing happened,&amp;rdquo; Jeff said. &amp;ldquo;They spent billions of dollars checking every line of code. But here, of course, they&amp;rsquo;re cheap bastards, so they didn&amp;rsquo;t bother doing any testing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not at all?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Zilch. Zero testing. Nada. And lo and behold, when people staggered back into work on January 2nd, not a single thing worked. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t print production schedules. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t get half of the assembly lines to even turn on. And nobody knew what shifts they were supposed to be working. The factory literally came to a standstill.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re kidding,&amp;rdquo; Ashton said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I shit you not. The factory was totally silent. Now, Charlie, she was new then. She had been working at Microsoft, or NASA, or something&amp;#8230; nobody could figure out why someone like her would be working in our little armpit of a company. But she sat down, and she started coding. And coding. And coding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Charlie coded for nine days straight. Nine days without sleeping, without eating, some people even claimed she never went to the bathroom. She went from system to system and literally fixed all of them. It was something to behold. My God, there were&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;COBOL&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;systems in there that needed to be fixed. The whole factory at a standstill, and Charlie is sending people to the university library in Ann Arbor to find old COBOL manuals. Assembly-line workers are standing around shivering, because even the&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;thermostats&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;had a Y2K bug. And Charlie is drinking cup after cup of coffee and typing like a madwoman.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow. And she never went to the bathroom?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, that part might be a&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;bit of an exaggeration. But she really did work 24 hours for nine days straight. Anyway, on January 11th, about five minutes before the day shift is supposed to start, she comes out of her cubicle, goes to the line printer, hits a button, and boom! out comes the production schedules, and the team schedules, and everything is perfect, perfectly formatted, using a slightly smaller font so that the &amp;ldquo;2000&amp;rdquo; fits where it used to say &amp;ldquo;99,&amp;rdquo; and she&amp;rsquo;s even written a new priority optimizing system that helps them catch up with 9 days of missed production without pissing off too many customers, and all the assembly lines start running like nothing was ever wrong, and the heat comes on, and the invoices come out printed with &amp;lsquo;2000&amp;rsquo; as the year instead of &amp;lsquo;19100,&amp;rsquo; and after that day, nobody found a single bug.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh come on!&amp;rdquo; Ashton says. &amp;ldquo;Nobody writes code without bugs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She did. I saw it with my own eyes. The first day back they ran two days worth of cubicles without a hiccup.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ashton was dumbstruck. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s epic. How can I live up to that?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t, buddy, nobody can,&amp;rdquo; Jeff said, turning back to his computer terminal, where he resumed an online flame war over who would win in a fight, Spock or Batman, which had been raging for over four months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not one to give up, Ashton swore he would, one day, do something legendary. But the truth is, there never was another Y2K. And nobody, in that part of Michigan, gave a rat&amp;rsquo;s ass about good programming. There was almost nothing for the programmers to do, in fact. Ashton got dumb little projects assigned to him&amp;#8230; at one point he spent three weeks working on handling a case where the sales tax in one particular county was wrong because some zip code spanned two different sales tax zones. The funny thing was, it was in some unpopulated part of New York State where nobody ever bought office cubicles, and they had never had a customer there, so his code would never run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For two years Ashton came into work enthusiastic and excited, and dying to make a difference and do something terrific and awesome, while his coworkers surfed the Internet, sent instant messages to their friends, and played computer solitaire for hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeff, his cubicle-mate, only had one responsibility: updating the weekly Excel spreadsheet indicating how many people were hurt on the job that week. Nobody ever was. Once a week, Jeff opened the spreadsheet, went to the bottom of the page, entered the date and a zero, hit save, and that was that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ashton even wrote a macro for Jeff that automated that one task. Jeff didn&amp;rsquo;t want to get caught, so he refused to install it. They weren&amp;rsquo;t on speaking terms after that. It was awkward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of his two year anniversary at the cubicle company, Ashton was driving to work when he realized something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not one line of code that he had written had ever run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not one thing he had done in two years of work made any impact on the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it was fucking 24 degrees in that part of Michigan, and it was gray, and smelly, and his Honda was a piece of crap, and he didn&amp;rsquo;t have any friends in town, and nothing he did mattered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As he drove down Lincoln Avenue, he saw the furniture company ahead on the left. Three flags fluttered in front of the corporate campus: an American flag, a flag of the great state of Michigan, and a white and red flag with the company logo. He got in the turning lane behind a long line of cars waiting to turn left. It always took four or five traffic light cycles, at rush hour, to make the turn, so Ashton had plenty of time to try to remember if any code he had&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;written was&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;used by&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it hadn&amp;rsquo;t. And he fought back a tear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And instead of turning left, he went straight, almost causing an accident because he forgot that the left turn light didn&amp;rsquo;t mean you could go straight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And he drove right down Lincoln Avenue, and got onto the Gerald Ford freeway, and he just kept driving until he got to the airport over in Grand Rapids, and he left his crappy old Honda out right in front of the terminal, knowing perfectly well it would be towed, and didn&amp;rsquo;t even close the car door, and he walked right up to the Frontier Airlines counter and he bought himself a ticket on the very next flight to San Francisco, which was leaving in 20 minutes, and he got on the plane, and he left Michigan forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shamelessly copied from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fogcreek.com/&quot;&gt;Joel Spolsky&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://programmers.stackexchange.com/questions/25432/how-can-a-new-programmer-impress-the-software-engineer-boss&quot;&gt;answer&lt;/a&gt; on the Programmers Stack Exchange.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-8186270854253329627?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google Buzz for iPhone</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/google-buzz-for-iphone"/>
   <updated>2010-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/google-buzz-for-iphone</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey guys &amp;#8212; a quick note, as these last few weeks have been hectic, putting the final touches on a client of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polsense.com&quot;&gt;Polsense&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; iOS application. Just wanted to say that my Google Buzz for iPhone app is now available in the App Store. It&amp;#8217;s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://buzzesapp.com&quot;&gt;Buzzes&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s free, so &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polsense.com&quot;&gt;get it&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;now!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 320px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Buzz-0.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1287462682830&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-7107894068652472291?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>RIM PlayBook Reaction</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/rim-playbook-reaction"/>
   <updated>2010-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/rim-playbook-reaction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a comment I tried to post on BlackBerryPR.net&amp;#8217;s blog. No thanks to IntenseDebate, I wasn&amp;#8217;t able to post it because it was too long. What the hell? What kind of shitty commenting platform penalizes commenters for saying too much? Would you rather prefer trollish one-liner comments?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here it is, in spanish:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;Realmente no le he podido dedicar mucho tiempo a estudiar la PlayBook. Estoy de lleno en desarrollo para otras plataformas y sinceramente, una tablet de RIM no me llama la atenci&amp;oacute;n para nada. Lo digo en el contexto de que, aun cuando estoy muy ocupado, si veo que hay algun anuncio nuevo de un producto muy atractivo, aunque sea le voy a dedicar 5 minutos a ver que hay nuevo. Pero sinceramente cuando vi que se anuncio el PlayBook, no me intereso leer nada sobre el equipo hasta que me avisas sobre este articulo.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;Solo dejandome llevar por lo que pones aqui, y habiendo hecho la aclaraci&amp;oacute;n de que no le he dedicado tiempo suficiente al tema para hacerle justicia, estas son mis observaciones:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;1. Adobe AIR y Adobe Flash support - Cool, que bueno que lo corre, pero buena suerte bregando con el power management. No se que bateria tiene pero esmandau hizo el comentario sobre esto y pues solo quiero a&amp;ntilde;adir que dudo que Flash ayude mucho en extender la duraci&amp;oacute;n de una sola carga.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;No solo la bateria, si no el problema que Flash trae a cualquier plataforma: esta dise&amp;ntilde;ado para correr en multiples plataformas y no una especifica. Mientras que eso es bien atractivo por el hecho de que un solo desarrollo te permite presencia en multiples plataformas, asi por igual es su mayor deficiencia, ya que el resultado es algo promedio, quizas mediocre, all across the board, en vez de concentrarse en una sola plataforma y hacer el mejor uso del dispositivo. Esto es algo no especifico a PlayBook pero sino a Flash en general. Incluso cuando un Android con Froyo va a una pagina a ver un video de Flash, tienes problemas interactuando con el player que no esta hecho para touch input, si necesitas hovers ya tienes problemas. Esto se puede contraarrestar con gestures que imiten hovers (el iPad usualmente permite un click rapido para hover y un click mas largo para un click regular, pero hay que programar para esto especificamente), pero sigue el mismo problema, no estas haciendo uso completo de la plataforma nativa.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;Claro, esto es algo que tambien puede ocurrir con HTML5, pero al menos la tendencia es que se esta yendo a HTML5 como solucion a la falta de Flash en movil y pues ya desde un principio se tiene en mente que el resultado funcione igual de bien en movil que en desktop. Pero esto va mas alla de Flash y HTML5, es web design en general que ya desde el a&amp;ntilde;o pasado los lideres en la industria siguen la filosofia de &amp;#8220;mobile first, desktop second.&amp;#8221;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;En fin, el argumento contra apps de Flash es que la mayoria estan hechos para el desktop, hay que comoquiera ajustarlos para que usen completamente el espacio movil sea Android, PlayBook, WebOS pero si ya vas a hacer ese esfuerzo, que te cuesta empezar con HTML5? Y a lo que voy es que, al fin de cuentas, el apoyo de Flash y Adobe AIR me da la impresion de un feature &amp;#8220;look at me! we run flash! we&amp;#8217;re better!&amp;#8221; en vez de ser mas forward-looking y dedicar esos recursos al SDK nativo.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;2. Lo que me lleva al desarrollo nativo, por supuesto. No he visto el SDK, si es que ya esta disponible o no, solo veo que el lenguaje es C/C++. Eso es lo de menos, really&amp;#8230; iOS es ObjectiveC, que de primera instancia asusta, pero hace total sentido ya que Apple lleva a&amp;ntilde;os de a&amp;ntilde;os trabajando en esta infraestructura en OS X y el SDK aun cuando salio en 2008, trae todo este peso de a&amp;ntilde;os de experiencia detras, donde realmente cualquier desarrollador de OS X puede hacer el brinco en 5 minutos. Y yo, que lo que hacia era Java, solo me tomo unos dias. Asi que no voy a tomar el que sea C++ como algo negativo. Lo que si es que pudieron haber aprovechado e irse con .NET, juntarse con Miguel de Icaza y traer su experiencia en MonoTouch, y seria tremendo ver que por un lado esta Apple con Cocoa, Android con Java, y Microsoft y RIM pooling resources into .NET. Les podria ir muy bien si se aferraran a Java o .NET y asi robaran desarrolladores de estas plataformas facilmente, ahora pues necesitan desarrolladores que quieran tirarse la maroma de ir a un lenguaje mas lower level y menos friendly, aunque mucho mas poderoso, sin el atractivo del App Store.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;Pero en fin, lo mas que les va a ayudar es hacer una buena conferencia de desarrolladores (eso hicieron ahora me imagino?), dar buenos talleres, estar ahi siempre dando la mano y crear la comunidad. Yo llevo dos a&amp;ntilde;os pagando par de miles de dolares cada vez tirandome el viaje a San Francisco para la conferencia de Apple porque le saco el jugo a eso todo el resto del a&amp;ntilde;o. Cinco mil otros devs hacen lo mismo, es evidencia del fuerte de la comunidad alrededor del desarrollo para OS X y iOS.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;Non-dev comment:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;Algo que me preocupa de cualquier tablet de 7&amp;#8221; incluyendo si Apple se tira una iPad de ese tama&amp;ntilde;o, es el teclado. Con iPhone y otros telefonos, es facil usar thumb typing. Con iPad, lo pones landscape y puedes usar las dos manos como si fuera un teclado fisico. Si lo pongo portrait, tengo que usar los pulgares y es mas dificil escribir rapido. Me imagino que el portrait de la iPad 9&amp;#8221; de ahora, se podria decir que es igual al landscape de un tablet de 7&amp;#8221;, y pues ni imaginar el portrair de 7&amp;#8221;, asi que tendria que usarlo para ver que tal. Claro, 9&amp;#8221; es un problema para cargar facilmente pero es un buen compromiso entre un iPhone y una laptop. Asi que me preocupa la tendencia de todos estos tablets usando 7&amp;#8221; como su tama&amp;ntilde;o&amp;#8230;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;_mcePaste&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;Eso es todo por ahora. Mientras vaya saliendo mas informacion puedo ir cambiando de opinion, pero como todo producto, tienen que llamar la atenci&amp;oacute;n y mostrar sus ventajas para crear esa comunidad. Fallas y terminas solo fragmentando un poco de la comunidad de desarrollo de otras plataformas y no logras tener algo self-sufficient. Mira a WebOS, tardaron demasiado en sacar su SDK nativo, aun cuando sus apps de HTML5 permitian mucha flexibilidad y el OS era de los mejores. Puede RIM hacer mejor trabajo que Palm en eso?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-513781518412562124?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Startups And Puerto Rico's Dim Future</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/on-startups-and-puerto-rico-dim-future"/>
   <updated>2010-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/on-startups-and-puerto-rico-dim-future</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I write this, the backup power supply beeps to let me know I have only 10 minutes left until I lose power. The only light source in here is my laptop&amp;#8217;s monitor, and its 300 feet through various dark hallways to the nearest exit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s 4:40 PM on a sunny Saturday afternoon in Puerto Rico, and the lights have gone out in my office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;14-September-2009 - Milla de Oro at night HDR by I Am Rob, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/robertrex365/3920924479/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3428/3920924479_35127472d4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14-September-2009 - Milla de Oro at night HDR&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To those that follow me on Twitter, you know that this is not a new occurrence. Power is constantly going out at my office and at my apartment. Like it or not, living without electric service is a mainstay of life in a tropical island. A couple of weeks ago the whole of the metropolitan area surrounding San Juan lost service hours before Hurricane Earl passed by. The head of the AEE (Puerto Rico&amp;#8217;s power company) could only lay blame on standard everyday outages, rather than admit that their network went down hours before the arrival of the storm.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With leadership like this, and a distribution network that nobody can rely on, how can Puerto Rico even think there is a chance of getting its stuff together?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Milla de Oro, Hato Rey by I Am Rob, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/robertrex365/4560910432/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3574/4560910432_e487702caa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Milla de Oro, Hato Rey&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems like the only way some one living in Puerto Rico can get through the day is by taking a government job or settling for a corporate office job. If by any chance you are considering starting a new business, the costs may very well be too high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;When your office suffers a power outage, productivity levels go down the drain as employees seek&amp;nbsp;coffee shops with Wi-Fi - that is, after they suffer a two-hour traffic jam to get home and find out power is out back home, too. If that&amp;#8217;s not enough, then the rent that goes with leasing a better office in a building that has a power generator will. That won&amp;#8217;t do much to help, anyway, since the Cable Internet provider for the metropolitan area is so horrendous, it will be very likely that you won&amp;#8217;t have online access anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/naturallyabel/2589500130/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3033/2589500130_025ecaed06.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284843589108&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;183&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is this post, more than another one of my rants? This post is my commitment to get out of this energy-draining, so-called &amp;#8216;paradise&amp;#8217; within two years. Two years ago I made the same commitment to get out of my corporate job and join a startup - I think leaving this island is the next logical step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-3445698610958202663?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Followup: Why Startups Outside Tech Cities Aren't Totally Farked</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/followup-why-startups-outside-tech"/>
   <updated>2010-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/followup-why-startups-outside-tech</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Living outside of Silicon Valley is not entirely bad, as my previous post might make you think. Here&amp;#8217;s an &lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2010/09/18/why-startups-outside-tech-cities-arent-totally-farked/&quot;&gt;interesting piece by Drew Curtis&lt;/a&gt; who owns Kentucky-based &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fark.com&quot;&gt;Fark&lt;/a&gt;. He covers the benefits of living outside the big cities:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cost of living is extremely low, and office space is cheap and plentiful. Traffic is pretty mild; Lexington has one of the five&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.americantowns.com/ky/lexington-information&quot;&gt;fastest median commute times in the country&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;nbsp;19.3 minutes (people who work at home weren&amp;rsquo;t counted). &amp;nbsp;Energy costs are some of the lowest in the United States (yay coal). &amp;nbsp;Real estate is cheap, both residential and commercial. It&amp;rsquo;s not very difficult to find houses for sale around here for $66 per square foot;&amp;nbsp;$150,000 for a 2,500-square-foot, four-bedroom home probably sounds amazing to people crammed in a NYC apartment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this might not be entirely true for San Juan, Puerto Rico. These reasons are the same I gave myself four years ago when I graduated from college and turned down various job offers in the States. I could stay in Puerto Rico, it&amp;#8217;s less expensive and I can give back to my country!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pshaw. A $150,000 apartment? Outside of the city, perhaps, which is easily an hour to two hours of commute in heavy traffic each way. I live in Trujillo Alto and even when I worked in nearby Cupey, that was 40 minutes if traffic was light during the morning, then 50 minutes on the drive back in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cable internet is more or less $50 for 4Mbps down, and shitty 0.5Mbps up, and that&amp;#8217;s with a one-year contract. Most other options are around $60 - $90 for 2Mbps DSL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further down, Drew mentions that Lexington is one non-stop flight away from the big tech cities. Taking a flight as necessary is cheaper than living full time in San Francisco, for example. I wish the same could be said about Puerto Rico, but being in the middle of the Caribbean Sea means one thing: it&amp;#8217;s at the very least 1.000 miles to the nearest state. A trip to San Francisco is easily 12 hours from take off to final landing, usually going through a two hour layover in DFW or LAX. Airfare? $600 if you&amp;#8217;re lucky.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for infrastructure, read my &lt;a href=&quot;/journal/2010/9/18/on-startups-and-puerto-ricos-dim-future.html&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;. Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will keep fighting the good fight, helping my entrepreneurial friends and organizing events for startup-minded folks, but as Drew says, there must be more execution and less talking about it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you think about running a startup in Puerto Rico?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-3326214182220315792?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Deeper Look At The New Twitter</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/deeper-look-at-new-twitter"/>
   <updated>2010-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/deeper-look-at-new-twitter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2010-09-15 at 12.16.10 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284567423677&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last night I posted a quick &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hectorramos.com/journal/2010/9/14/a-first-look-at-the-new-twitter.html&quot;&gt;first look&lt;/a&gt; at New Twitter&amp;#8217;s revamped website. Now I have been able to use it for a few hours and seeing some new features that quickly make this New Twitter my new favorite way of consuming the stream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what has changed? Twitter is trying to expose its platforms strengths and set itself apart from other social networks - Ev himself said that Twitter is not a social network. The key to Twitter is the quick and easy distribution of information without geographical boundaries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is achieved through various concepts. While Twitter is built on top of a social graph, these connections are weaker than those on Facebook. The latter&amp;#8217;s social graph is traditionally based on friends and acquaintances and family. But as all of us who receive chain letters from a distant family member know, this strong social graph does not work as well for sharing interesting bits of information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2010-09-15 at 12.17.34 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284567488429&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is Twitter&amp;#8217;s strength. Each user curates its own Following and Followers lists, resulting in a timeline that is very effective at surfacing interesting information. This automated filtering is what has people wrongly stating that RSS is dead&lt;sup&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;#ftn.id091520101&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;id091520101&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/sup&gt;. Your Following list has first class access to your timeline, each tweet given a fair chance at appearing in your timeline. These are the people you trust to constantly discover and share important or interesting information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your Followers list, which is not constrained by your Following list, complements your timeline by commenting on your tweets and sharing additional information through the use of mentions. This is how you can have a small list of Following while still being able to read information from your bigger list of Followers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third and final component is, of course, Lists. These are custom Following timelines that can be created and destroyed at will without cluttering your main timeline. Interested in iPhone development only during the day? Don&amp;#8217;t follow developers on your main timeline, follow an &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/ravenme/iphone&quot;&gt;iOS Developers list&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202010-09-15%20at%2012.13.30%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-8558471-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284567342209&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having established the various ways your Timeline is curated, lets go back to one of the new features: inline media. This has long been a feature used by third party developers to set themselves apart. Embedding media in your timeline is a great timesaver, as most of the time a simple picture can be viewed by itself within the context of a tweet, without a need to visit the originating website. The New Twitter presents these embedded pictures right in the sidebar. Heck, try sharing a Flickr set, you will even get a gallery of thumbnails right there without leaving Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2010-09-15 at 12.24.09 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284567875334&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;This inline presentation of media works so well, that Twitter has now earned its place as a Pinned Tab in Chrome. Whomever made the favicon had that in mind as it already has an embossed line that fits perfectly with the design of Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2010-09-15 at 12.27.19 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284568069358&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;But what is probably my favorite new feature of all is the new VIM-style keyboard shortcuts that follow Gmail&amp;#8217;s example. Just hit ? to bring up the Help panel to get yourself up to date with these shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2010-09-15 at 12.29.06 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284568189184&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sure we will see many posts throughout the upcoming days crying over Twitter&amp;#8217;s abandonment of developers and how they&amp;#8217;ve turned their back on them. That couldn&amp;#8217;t be further from the truth. The New Twitter is built using the same API available to developers, there is nothing preventing anyone from building a superior product. Before you claim that they have the upper hand since they are, well, Twitter, give it a second thought. They built the platform. They opened their API for all of you. While you can claim that third party apps helped with Twitter&amp;#8217;s growth, the facts show that most users still go through Twitter&amp;#8217;s web interface, SMS and their own official Twitter apps. Without Twitter, your third party applications would be useless. You might have been successful by building on top of someone else&amp;#8217;s platform, but honestly that is equivalent to picking off pennies from in front of an incoming train. As a developer, you have to always be careful when building features that can easily be in the platform&amp;#8217;s roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter is used in very different ways by each user, so there is still plenty of space in the platform to set yourself apart as a third party client. Take, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://claritty.com&quot;&gt;Claritty&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to use filters to clean up your timeline, that is something that you won&amp;#8217;t see in Twitter for a long time, so your only option is to use a third party alternative. Are you a brand manager? &lt;a href=&quot;http://tweetdeck.com&quot;&gt;Tweetdeck&lt;/a&gt; might be your best friend. If you have many employees in your team managing a single account, you&amp;#8217;ll want to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cotweet.com&quot;&gt;CoTweet&lt;/a&gt;. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s all for now. I&amp;#8217;ve got to get back to work. There&amp;#8217;s a few more topics I&amp;#8217;d like to discuss, such as monetization and the future of the Twitter platform, so hopefully I&amp;#8217;ll set aside some time in the next few days. I&amp;#8217;ve been busy working in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polsense.com&quot;&gt;new startup&lt;/a&gt; but in the next few weeks I should be blogging more here and at &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.polsense.com&quot;&gt;Polsense&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2010-09-15 at 12.42.24 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284568963020&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1&lt;a name=&quot;ftn.id091520101&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/sup&gt; RSS is what made news readers such as Google Reader possible. Just a couple of years ago, I lived within Google Reader every day, scouring for interesting articles. Now I barely log into Reader, trusting that whatever is important enough will surface on my Twitter timeline. Still, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/09/13/howToRebootRss.html&quot;&gt;RSS is a key component to information distribution&lt;/a&gt; and without this lower level network, your Twitter timeline would have a harder time discovering this information.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A First Look At The New Twitter</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/first-look-at-new-twitter"/>
   <updated>2010-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/first-look-at-new-twitter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; has hatched and is now more realtime than ever. The rapidly growing service is no longer about tweeting, but about discovery. As Ev said earlier today, you don&amp;#8217;t have to tweet to use Twitter. Following on this premise, the new Twitter is dynamic and fast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-inline ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202010-09-14%20at%207.41.32%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-8549415-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Images and videos can now be viewed from Twitter.com itself. Up until today, third party websites filled these niches as a way of setting themselves apart. Twitter will not host these files, so there is still a place for some of these services, but media embedding should no longer be a sole primary feature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202010-09-14%20at%207.51.14%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-8549483-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To emphasize discovery, the search bar is now featured prominently in the header of the new Twitter website. Selecting a tweet will open a new pane in the side bar which will include extra information such as the user&amp;#8217;s timeline. If the tweet contains a link to pictures or videos, it will automatically be embedded in this side bar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202010-09-14%20at%207.52.40%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-8549520-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1284508456389&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replying to tweets is now even smoother, with a new popup that lets you tweet without scrolling to the top input form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202010-09-14%20at%207.49.46%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-8549543-thumbnail.jpg?&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Viewing mentions, retweets and lists are also faster now as they will load in the same column without refreshing the website. These dropdown lists make accessing all your lists so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202010-09-14%20at%207.56.12%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-8549607-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new Twitter will be slowly rolling out worldwide. Having only used it for five minutes, it looks very sleek but I will need some more time to go through all of the new features. Look for an update later.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Objective See</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/objective-see"/>
   <updated>2010-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/objective-see</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I find it much simpler to share quick updates and links on my Tumblr, so I&amp;#8217;ve added it as a sub-domain: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hectorramos.com&quot;&gt;http://blog.hectorramos.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I realize it might be a little confusing to have two blogs, but consider this main Journal as more of a source of infrequent articles while the Blog might have more frequent short updates. I&amp;#8217;ll see how I can merge these later into a single page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-4362678957644552120?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Building a website? HTML5 boiler plates</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/boiler-plates"/>
   <updated>2010-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/boiler-plates</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ve been reading about HTML5&amp;#8217;s new features for months. You sit down and set out to write a new website - do you remember all the best practices?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;HTML5 boiler plates take care of this initial hurdle for you. Here are two that I&amp;#8217;m currently using in some upcoming projects:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://html5boilerplate.com/&quot;&gt;HTML5 Boiler Plate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://html5reset.org/&quot;&gt;HTML5 Reset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t just extract the code and do minor adjustments. This is a great opportunity to see HTML5 code that has been carefully tended to by groups of web developers for months.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quick Update: WWDC10 &amp; Beyond</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/quick-update-wwdc10"/>
   <updated>2010-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/quick-update-wwdc10</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks have been hectic, so I&amp;#8217;ll keep it short.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. I&amp;#8217;m leaving for &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/wwdc/&quot;&gt;Apple&amp;#8217;s Worldwide Developer&amp;#8217;s Conference 2010&lt;/a&gt; in a short few hours. This is going to be my second year. This time I&amp;#8217;m heading out alone, so if you see me around, come and say hi :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. I quit my job. Will be working now fulltime with iPhone and iPad development, amongst other things. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. The best way to keep up to date with my POV coverage of WWDC is through my &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/hramos&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; and Twitter accounts. Follow @hectorramos !&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-8804411021696647810?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gowalla Spots In Puerto Rico</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/gowalla-spots-in-puerto-rico"/>
   <updated>2010-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/gowalla-spots-in-puerto-rico</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;col-z12qyvazeoqxdrog404ccjfgwtm2zpryu3k&quot; class=&quot;zG9tqc z19Dle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;zo&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;HgYomf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sDgL9b Ig QGJaM&quot; style=&quot;display: block;&quot;&gt;Last Thursday I &amp;#8220;launched&amp;#8221; @GowallaSpotsPR, a hastily thrown  together mash up that monitors Gowalla spots around Puerto Rico and  tweets out all the new spots it finds. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;On Friday, I added Hot Spots to the list - any trending spots will  be tweeted out as well. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;This project has been worked on for all of two hours between  Thursday and Friday, after which I left for a weekend getaway in the  mountains of Puerto Rico so I was unable to monitor and adjust the  service during the weekend. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I know some of you have some suggestions, so let me know in this  thread what you would like to see. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;@luisjv commented  on the spamming whenever there are many new spots. I currently have it  set so that it will tweet out a maximum of six new spots, with the last  tweet pointing out how many new spots where not tweeted due to the hard  limit of six. I thought this would be enough, since it only runs once an  hour, but I agree that it can become annoying if there are many spots  being created during the day. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I want to know - is it fine the way it is, since only Gowalla fans  would follow it anyway and would still be interested in this  information, or should I lower the limit? &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Would it be better, then, to run the service twice per hour? This  would hopefully split the updates in half. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;@arkhangel also suggested a way to find dupe spots. I&amp;#8217;m  going to think about this, I could probably use the GPS and name to mark  which are suspected dupes. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also considering opening up an RSS feed of all the spots, and  adding geolocation data to the tweets sent out, so that you can see the  location of the spots from your favorite Twitter client without going  into the Gowalla website.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-3390381903174960609?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>COM:LINK 1.1 Now Available</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/now-available"/>
   <updated>2010-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/now-available</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Roughly one week after being &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hectorramos.com/journal/2010/5/3/comlink-11-update-soon.html&quot;&gt;submitted&lt;/a&gt;, the 1.1 update to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hectorramos.com/apps/comlink.html&quot;&gt;COM:LINK&lt;/a&gt; is now &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=322502765&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;available in the App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among squashing various bugs that should fix most communication drops, I&amp;#8217;ve added a new setting to &lt;em&gt;lock&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;the Talk Button. Access it from the new in-app Menu found at the bottom of your COM:LINK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There you will also be able to buy an upgrade to COM:LINK+ which can also send pictures to other COM:LINK users. The upgrade is for the lifetime of the COM:LINK app, so expect future updates to add to the COM:LINK+ repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-6113683011857353266?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>COM:LINK 1.1 Update Soon</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/update-soon"/>
   <updated>2010-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/update-soon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spent the weekend adding some new features that have been a long time in the To Do bucket for COM:LINK. Submitted the binary late last night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/apps/comlink.html&quot;&gt;COM:LINK&lt;/a&gt; is one of my personal iPhone apps, which has enjoyed great success in the App Store thanks to Japan. Even 8 months after initially appearing in the App Store, it is seeing around 300 downloads per day on average.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the problems of working with Bluetooth paired applications is that you need two devices to test on. This was not much of a problem last summer, since I had an iPhone 3G and iPhone 3GS to test with. I also borrowed an iPod Touch for a while, since the Touch was the main target for the application. In the months after submitting COM:LINK, I gave my 3G to my dad and gave back the iPod Touch, so I was stuck with a single iPhone and no way of testing updates to COM:LINK. Now that I have an iPad, I was able to resume work on COM:LINK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;First feature to be checked off from the To Do list is the Talk Button Lock. Lots of people have asked me if it was possible to have the Talk Button stay On without having to hold it down. Making the button stick was a quick change, but this required the addition of a preference menu where the user could turn on and off this setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I could have gone with the standard Settings bundle, which places the option in the Settings app, however I felt it broke the flow of the app, so I went with an in-app menu that slides up from the bottom of the device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another hurdle was working with plist setting files, something that should have been quite easy to implement, however I was having some issues with persistence. Lost some hours chasing bugs, in the end found it much simpler to go with CoreData, as I have in all of my other apps since COM:LINK&amp;#8217;s creation. It might seem like overkill, but it did the job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next on the list was adding In-App Purchases. I need to recoup the time investment, but I felt that asking users to pay for a simple, fun walkie-talkie app was too much. Using In-App Purchases provides a middle ground - everyone can keep using the app for free, but if you feel like cooperating you can upgrade to COM:LINK+.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, if I am going to provide a paid upgrade, I need to pair it with new features. New for 1.1 and COM:LINK+, you can now send photos to other COM:LINK devices. What&amp;#8217;s neat about this is that your friend does not need to have COM:LINK+ in order to receive your photos. Only the Sender needs to upgrade to COM:LINK+. Of course, you might want to tell your friends to upgrade, too, so that they may be able to send photos back to you. ;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sending photos is just the first of some COM:LINK+ features on the way. The plan is to keep COM:LINK working perfectly for radio communication, while adding new features to COM:LINK+. This way, everybody keeps the same app they&amp;#8217;ve been enjoying for the last year, while having the option to upgrade and use newer features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-6624619531522787192?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mint for Android</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/mint-for-android"/>
   <updated>2010-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/mint-for-android</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personal finance site&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mint.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mint.com&lt;img id=&quot;snap_com_shot_link_icon&quot; class=&quot;snap_preview_icon&quot; src=&quot;http://i.ixnp.com/images/v6.28/t.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;has&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businesswire.com/portal/site/home/permalink/?ndmViewId=news_view&amp;amp;newsId=20100503005791&amp;amp;newsLang=en&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;debuted&lt;img id=&quot;snap_com_shot_link_icon&quot; class=&quot;snap_preview_icon&quot; src=&quot;http://i.ixnp.com/images/v6.28/t.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;its Android app today, which lets Mint.com users access a complete snapshot of their financial picture and manage their finances on the go. Mint.com, a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2007/09/18/mint-wins-techcrunch40-50000-award/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch40&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;company that was acquired by Intuit for&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2009/09/13/intuit-to-acquire-former-techcrunch50-winner-mint-for-170-million/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;$170 million&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;last fall,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.zdnet.com/BTL/?p=28923&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;initially announced&lt;img id=&quot;snap_com_shot_link_icon&quot; class=&quot;snap_preview_icon&quot; src=&quot;http://i.ixnp.com/images/v6.28/t.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;the development of the free app last November.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2010/05/03/mint-com-debuts-android-app/#ixzz0msYzR8UH&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://techcrunch.com/2010/05/03/mint-com-debuts-android-app/#ixzz0msYzR8UH&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the release of the Android app, along with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popular.com/westernbank/index-en.html&quot;&gt;Friday&amp;#8217;s events&lt;/a&gt;, even more Puerto Ricans will be able to use Mint to manage their finances while on the move.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-294922433222348207?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>WWDC 2010 in early June</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/in-early-june"/>
   <updated>2010-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/in-early-june</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/wwdc10.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1272550762629&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple has finally announced the dates for this year&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/wwdc/&quot;&gt;Worldwide Developer&amp;#8217;s Conference&lt;/a&gt;: June 7 - 11. The announcement has been expected since mid-March, when they usually set the final dates. Although this year&amp;#8217;s dates match up with last year&amp;#8217;s, it is still a little weird to still have the conference 5 weeks from the announcement. We now need to scurry and make arrangements, both travel-wise and project-wise, to be able to be in San Francisco for the second week of June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hramos/3608676202/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2434/3608676202_1592eae291.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1272550871703&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;WWDC09 was focused on Snow Leopard and iPhone OS 3.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another unexpected change, but that actually makes sense due to the proximity of the conference, is that this year Apple is not offering an early buyer discount. While last year the Conference Ticket was $1,299 for the first few weeks, and then $1,599 starting on April 24th, this year the Ticket price is a flat out $1,599 from the get go. Last year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tuaw.com/2009/04/28/wwdc-09-is-a-sellout-time-to-call-your-ticket-scalper/&quot;&gt;WWDC09 sold out&lt;/a&gt; on April 28th, just like the previous year in mid-May.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hramos/4561541645/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3064/4561541645_83f66e43e4.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1272550886911&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;Ouch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not wanting to risk getting left out of WWDC2010, I bought my ticket yesterday as soon as I heard the news. Seems like Apple is expecting a third sold out conference and as such is not considering early buyer discounts. WWDC09 was a very organized event, the Wi-Fi never died out, and we had lots of coffee and snacks through out the day, in addition to the complimentary breakfast and lunch (plus Thursday&amp;#8217;s CAKE Bash which had free dinner and booze).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t miss out this year. Buy your ticket today before it sells out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hramos/3606018518/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3405/3606018518_811143042d.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1272550908334&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;Overlooking San Francisco from the Marin Headlands&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-3732250333732242708?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Using Mint as a BPPR customer, Part II</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/using-mint-as-bppr-customer-part-ii"/>
   <updated>2010-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/using-mint-as-bppr-customer-part-ii</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hectorramos.com/journal/2010/3/3/using-mint-as-a-bppr-customer.html&quot;&gt;guide on using Mint as a BPPR customer&lt;/a&gt;. Some people were able to get it to work, but the success rate was no way near 100%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks later, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mint.com&quot;&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt; changed the way they handled BPPR accounts, but only temporarily. Fortunately, Mint has resolved the situation and all BPPR customers should be able to link their online banking accounts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miguel Rios, of &lt;a href=&quot;http://noveltica.com/&quot;&gt;Noveltica&lt;/a&gt;, covers the steps that need to be done in order to &lt;a href=&quot;http://noveltica.com/nuevo-conecta-tu-cuenta-del-banco-popular-con-mint-com/&quot;&gt;link your BPPR accounts&lt;/a&gt;. Please note that you will need to search for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popular.com&quot;&gt;Banco Popular de Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;, as opposed to Popular (PR).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-8570750467443903091?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Startup Lessons Learned Conference Simulcast</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/startup-lessons-learned-conference"/>
   <updated>2010-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/startup-lessons-learned-conference</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d like to invite anyone in the, or near, San Juan area who is interested in lean startup methodologies to attend the &lt;a href=&quot;http://startups.eventbrite.com/&quot;&gt;simulcast&lt;/a&gt; that will be held at Gauss Research Laboratories this friday at noon. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://startuplessonslearnedsf.eventbrite.com/&quot;&gt;Startup Lessons Learned Conference&lt;/a&gt; will be live streamed, free of charge, all over the world in various cities. Fortunately, San Juan, PR has stepped up to join the 50 cities that will participate in the global simultaneous broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://startups.eventbrite.com/&quot;&gt;Please RSVP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the event description:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Startup Lessons Learned is the first event designed to unite those interested in what it takes to succeed in building a lean startup. The&amp;nbsp;goal for this event is to give practitioners and students of the lean startup methodology the opportunity to hear insights from leaders in embracing and deploying the core principles of the lean startup methodology. The day-long event will feature a mix of panels and talks focused on the key challenges and issues that technical and market-facing people at startups need to understand in order to succeed in building successful lean startups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Confirmed Speakers and Participating Mentors:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eric Ries, The Lean Startup (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ericries&quot;&gt;@ericries&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kent Beck, Three Rivers Institute (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/kentbeck&quot;&gt;@kentbeck&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Steve Blank (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/sgblank&quot;&gt;@sgblank&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Randy Komisar, Kleiner Perkins Caufield &amp;amp; Byers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Andrew Chen, Futuristic Play (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/andrew_chen&quot;&gt;@andrew_chen&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;David Weekly, PB Works (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/dweekly&quot;&gt;@dweekly&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hiten Shah, KISSmetrics (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/hnshah&quot;&gt;@hnshah&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cindy Alvarez, KISSmetrics (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/cindyalvarez&quot;&gt;@cindyalvarez&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ethan Bloch, Flowtown (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ebloch&quot;&gt;@ebloch&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Timothy Fitz, IMVU (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/timothyfitz&quot;&gt;@TimohtyFitz&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drew Houston, Dropbox (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/drewhouston&quot;&gt;@drewhouston&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ash Maurya, WiredReach (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ashmaurya&quot;&gt;@ashmaurya&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dave McClure (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/davemcclure&quot;&gt;@davemcclure&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sean Ellis (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/seanellis&quot;&gt;@seanellis&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Laura Klein (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/lauraklein&quot;&gt;@lauraklein&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Damon Horowitz, Aardvark / Google (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/iamnottweeting&quot;&gt;@iamnottweeting&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Max Ventilla, Aardvark / Google (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ventilla&quot;&gt;@ventilla&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Brant Cooper (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/BrantCooper&quot;&gt;@brantcooper&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clara Shih, Hearsay Labs (&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/clarashih&quot;&gt;@clarashih&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Manuel Rosso (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/manuelrosso&quot;&gt;@manuelrosso&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rashmi Sinha (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/rashmi&quot;&gt;@rashmi&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dan Martell, Flowtown (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/danmartell&quot;&gt;@danmartell&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Brett Durrett, IMVU&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;James Birchler, IMVU&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Andres Glusman, Meetup (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/glusman&quot;&gt;@glusman&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-106140379091108568?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The iPad has a Camera...</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/ipad-has-camera"/>
   <updated>2010-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/ipad-has-camera</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;and it&amp;#8217;s called &lt;a href=&quot;/apps/imageshare.html&quot;&gt;ImageShare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/apps/imageshare.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/original-4.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1270693130840&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;That is, if you also have an iPhone. Using my (long without updates) iPhone application on both the iPad and iPhone you can take pictures and have them transfered to your iPad immediately through the Bluetooth connection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply pair the iPad and iPhone by running &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hectorramos.com/apps/imageshare.html&quot;&gt;ImageShare&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on both. Select the Camera option when selecting which image to share, and snap your picture. Share it with your iPad and it will be saved to your local Photo Album.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll probably see a lot of hole-filling apps like these popup these next few days&amp;#8230; but you can start doing this with &lt;a href=&quot;itms://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=320375566&amp;amp;mt=8&amp;amp;s=143441&quot;&gt;ImageShare for free&lt;/a&gt; right now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hramos/4501184903/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4044/4501184903_acb400bb50.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1270694542975&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 375px;&quot;&gt;Once your iPhone has connected to your iPad through Bluetooth, take a picture from your iPhone. Like this one. So meta.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/hramos/4501820162/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4071/4501820162_54412ee445.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1270694577892&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 375px;&quot;&gt;Hit Send, and watch as your photo transfers immediately to your iPad. Have fun with your iPad&amp;#8217;s new camera!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-510846737883806549?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The iPad is (almost) here</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/ipad-is-almost-here"/>
   <updated>2010-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/ipad-is-almost-here</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Come April 3rd, thousands of customers will line up at Apple Stores and Best Buys across the nation to pick up their iPad. Some, however, will wait for the 3G version to become available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will wait for the 3G iPad, however, all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/business/article/0,8599,1976935,00.html&quot;&gt;positive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://ptech.allthingsd.com/20100331/apple-ipad-review/&quot;&gt;reviews&lt;/a&gt; keep pushing me towards the Wi-Fi iPad. Nah, I am a big GPS user, the wait is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/Luj263H_56A&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/Luj263H_56A&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you think? iPad 3G or iPad Wi-Fi?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/QIic04tXkRw&amp;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;color2=0xcfcfcf&amp;hl=en_US&amp;feature=player_embedded&amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowScriptAccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/QIic04tXkRw&amp;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;color2=0xcfcfcf&amp;hl=en_US&amp;feature=player_embedded&amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowScriptAccess=&quot;always&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-4498275253884646336?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SXSW Photo Recap</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-photo-recap"/>
   <updated>2010-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-photo-recap</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Paul did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulstamatiou.com/sxsw-interactive-2010-in-pictures&quot;&gt;great recap of SXSW 2010&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;that effectively captures the whole feeling of being in Austin during SXSW. Since I forgot my camera charger at home and my battery wasn&amp;#8217;t charged (yeah, horrible planning on my part) I wasn&amp;#8217;t able to snap many photos other than those taken on my iPhone. A shame, so I encourage you to check out his pictures to get an idea of how SXSW was this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/TNH6MuS3Ixc&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/TNH6MuS3Ixc&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sixth street was very busy during SXSWi but it wasn&amp;#8217;t until SXSW Music started that they closed it off. It was neat walking for blocks and blocks through crowds of happy, festive people, with lots of live music blaring around you. Paul shot the video above from the same perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s another video, this one by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dirtsalad.com/2010/03/28/sxsw/&quot;&gt;Glenn&lt;/a&gt;, a montage from all the pictures taken during SXSW:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=10499881&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=1&amp;amp;color=dd4499&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=10499881&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=1&amp;amp;color=dd4499&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of pictures I uploaded to &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/users/hramos/photos&quot;&gt;Gowalla&lt;/a&gt; during my trip. There&amp;#8217;s not much to see here, as I was more preoccupied with all the panels going on at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/checkins/4651089&quot;&gt;Texas State Capitol grounds&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/14142_high_res_320x480.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-6310142-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269801469494&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 150px;&quot;&gt;Inside the Capitol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/checkins/4650758&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 150px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/TEXAS_RANGER_14114_high_res_320x480.jpeg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269801285366&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 150px;&quot;&gt;Texas Ranger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/checkins/4651089&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 150px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/TEXAS_STATE_CAPITOL_14155_high_res_320x480.jpeg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269801346119&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 150px;&quot;&gt;Texas State Capitol Plaque&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/checkins/4658812&quot;&gt;One Taco&lt;/a&gt;, a tasty taco truck that partnered with Gowalla to give out random free tacos upon checkin:&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/15041_high_res_320x480.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-6310229-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269801723991&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/14803_high_res_320x480.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-6310158-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269801636715&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 150px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/15013_high_res_320x480.jpeg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269801666137&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of Google&amp;#8217;s new employees this year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://factoryjoe.com/&quot;&gt;Chris Messina&lt;/a&gt; during his &lt;a href=&quot;http://activitystrea.ms&quot;&gt;ActivityStreams&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/spots/671611&quot;&gt;panel&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/20359_high_res_320x480.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-6310242-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269801818934&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/jw&quot;&gt;Josh Williams&lt;/a&gt; of Gowalla during his talk at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/spots/671812&quot;&gt;Facebook Developer Garage&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/28473_high_res_320x480.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-6310298-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269802012114&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-3166856186889639439?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Meetup at The Office</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/meetup-at-office"/>
   <updated>2010-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/meetup-at-office</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/THE OFFICE - Traditional Irish Pub.jpeg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269809894229&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a new Irish pub close to my apartment in Trujillo Alto. It&amp;#8217;s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=129744091927&quot;&gt;The Office&lt;/a&gt;, a traditional &lt;a href=&quot;http://theofficetraditionalirishpub.webs.com/&quot;&gt;irish pub&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;The objective of The Office Traditional Irish Pub is to attract professionals, retired people, artists and musicians. We aim to&amp;nbsp; provide a healthy and educated and pleasant environment for everyone to feel at ease or sit around and talk. To share and relax with your friends. We will be offering an open stage for artists, poets and musicians (acoustic, classic and flamenco).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found it by chance and quickly fell in love with the place. We&amp;#8217;ve been frequenting it for the last couple of months, so much it has become a &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/spots/519257&quot;&gt;staple of our weekends&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hramos.posterous.com/nice-to-see-the-office-trending-in-gowalla&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/image.jpg.scaled500.jpeg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269809217659&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 320px;&quot;&gt;These past two weekends we&amp;#8217;ve got The Office to become a Hot Spot in Gowalla.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m glad that everyone seems to like the place so far. They have a great variety of imported beer, in addition to the usual found in Puerto Rico. If you like beer that is a little off the beaten path, you&amp;#8217;ll love this place. Tom and Joe are excellent hosts and they&amp;#8217;ll help you feel at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Episodes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enprofundo.com&quot;&gt;En Profundo&lt;/a&gt;, a new local podcast that covers a variety of timely topics, are routinely recorded in The Office. Last night, in addition to the usual crew from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frecuenciasalternas.com&quot;&gt;Frecuencias Alternas&lt;/a&gt; and En Profundo, we had the chance to meet up with a great group of friends which we only get to know through online networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;javascript:showFullImage('/display/ShowImage?imageUrl=%2Fstorage%2Fphoto.jpg%3F__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION%3D1269808927608',600,800);&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3374460-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269809554990&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Among those in attendance last night (starting with those in the picture above):@meebits, @arkhangel, @vanessaenid, @luiscrz, @mj16, @joeprog, @dr_zu, @therealgabo and his brother, @sumares, @eldifusor, @dianadhevi, @veedot, ex-@8008135, &amp;nbsp;@arsenic447, @popculturerobot, and myself, @hectorramos.&amp;nbsp;It was great to see all of you in the same place and look forward to more casual meetups such as this one in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/89143_high_res_320x480.jpeg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269810492431&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Geolocation Viz During South by SouthWest</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/geolocation-viz-during-south-by"/>
   <updated>2010-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/geolocation-viz-during-south-by</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The team from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simplegeo.com&quot;&gt;SimpleGeo&lt;/a&gt; have just released a visualization that displays the aggregated data from the top geolocation services used during &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sxsw.com&quot;&gt;South by SouthWest&lt;/a&gt; in Austin this month. These include checkins through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gowalla.com&quot;&gt;Gowalla&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foursquare.com&quot;&gt;foursquare&lt;/a&gt;, as well as geotagged Flickr photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/Gpypn-JIPng&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/Gpypn-JIPng&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my experience, Gowalla was the most useful geolocation service. Yes, I may be biased, as it is no secret that I am a huge fan, but the team really did their best to create a great experience for their users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the panels, events and venues had their own Gowalla featured spot already created, with a proper description and location. The spots were time-sensitive, meaning that they would only show up shortly before and during the related event. This helped a lot when scheduling which panels to go to, as all ongoing events were quickly highlighted. On top of that, any hot spot (events with an increased rate of checkins) were even more visible, making it all the easier to find the best venues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried using foursquare for the first few days as well, but it really was a bad user experience to wade through all the dupe, inconsistently named spots. I could rarely find the event for a panel I was in, even minutes after it had started. Still, I made use of its trending feature quite a lot, which is similar to the Hot Spots feature in Gowalla I just described.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It certainly was neat to be in a city full of users like us, checking in everywhere &amp;#8212; most venues would already have quite a few people already checked in. It&amp;#8217;s a different feeling from my home town, where checking in to the same place as another user on the same day is a rare sight. All in all, it was a great experience for both Gowalla and foursquare users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4308278671813780009-6594776305744802697?l=hector-omar.blogspot.com' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>9 Tips To South by Southwest For First Timers</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/tips-to-south-by-southwest-for-first"/>
   <updated>2010-03-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/tips-to-south-by-southwest-for-first</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/danah-boyd-opening.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269305362277&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 465px;&quot;&gt;Danah Boyd&amp;#8217;s opening remarks at SXSWi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been back in Puerto Rico for the last two days or so, decompressing from the trip to Austin and getting ready to get back to work. There is so much I want to write about the different panels and events I attended, but even after two days, I haven&amp;#8217;t got the notion of where to start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s start with what, exactly, is &amp;#8220;southby&amp;#8221; supposed to be. According to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_by_Southwest&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South by Southwest&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;strong&gt;SXSW&lt;/strong&gt;) is a set of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&quot;Interactive media&quot; href=&quot;/wiki/Interactive_media&quot;&gt;interactive&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&quot;Film&quot; href=&quot;/wiki/Film&quot;&gt;film&lt;/a&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&quot;Music&quot; href=&quot;/wiki/Music&quot;&gt;music&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;festivals and conferences that take place every spring in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&quot;Austin, Texas&quot; href=&quot;/wiki/Austin,_Texas&quot;&gt;Austin, Texas&lt;/a&gt;. SXSW first began in 1987 and is centered on the downtown&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&quot;Austin Convention Center&quot; href=&quot;/wiki/Austin_Convention_Center&quot;&gt;Austin Convention Center&lt;/a&gt;. Each of the three parts runs relatively independently, with different start and end dates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a teaser for SXSW2010 from last year (filmed at previous SXSWs):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/YSp1MQaqiSg&amp;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;color2=0xcfcfcf&amp;hl=en_US&amp;feature=player_embedded&amp;fs=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowScriptAccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/YSp1MQaqiSg&amp;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;color2=0xcfcfcf&amp;hl=en_US&amp;feature=player_embedded&amp;fs=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowScriptAccess=&quot;always&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The events I assisted formally are collectively known as SXSW Film+Interactive. The Gold Badge grants its wearer access to all the Film and Interactive tracks, badge events and film screenings throughout Austin. Interactive, by itself, lasted from March 12 to March 16. Film panels were held from March 12 to March 16 as well, but film screenings went on through March 20. The Music festival itself is held from March 17 to March 21.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2010-03-22 at 8.51.58 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269305577490&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a point that was initially confusing to me when I was arranging travel and lodging. I didn&amp;#8217;t want to leave while Film was still going on, but I was told that Music was too crazy. I ended up staying from March 11 to March 19 in Austin, which I believe was a great choice and worked out very well. I was able to go to the Interactive panels, and still had two days to catch up some film screenings I&amp;#8217;d missed - all while being able to take in the Music festivities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Music festival is another monster by itself - you can get Music badges (or the end-all Platinum which covers F+I as well), but there are also Music wristbands that allow you to get in to the live shows if you are not interested in the Music panels. The wristbands are much cheaper than a badge ($165 versus ~$700) and are the popular choice among attendees. On top of all that, there are SXXpress passes you may get a few hours before each event, which are limited to a % of the capacity of the venue and allow you to skip the lines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, what should you do next year for SXSW 2011 if it is going to be your first time? I am no SXSW expert, of course, this being just my first time, but there might be some value to you in these guidelines that may already be common sense amongst SXSW veterans and is not touched upon by the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Leave the laptop. Take your iPad.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless you are a journalist or blogger with the intention to liveblog the event, there is just no need for a laptop in the panels. Your typing might be distracting, you won&amp;#8217;t be able to focus on the discussion, and you will look like a dork walking around town with your backpack. Luckily, Austin is full of geeks like you during Interactive, so you won&amp;#8217;t stand out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, some nighttime venues don&amp;#8217;t allow two-strap bags in, as they can certainly occupy the space of an additional customer. I did take my laptop with me half of the time (you&amp;#8217;ll see why soon), but I tried to go back to the hotel or have someone take it back to me sometime between 5 and 7 PM so that I could enjoy the parties at night without extra burden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is where I can see the iPad shine. I certainly would feel naked if I travelled without my laptop, but I don&amp;#8217;t want to deal with the burden. Many Interactive attendees talked about and concurred that next year we won&amp;#8217;t see that many laptops, and instead we will see iPads all around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. If you have an iPhone, prepare yourself&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a battery pack - ideally a rechargeable one. Carry two, if possible. This year, Chevy had a recharge lounge, and lots of multiplugs spread throughout the Austin Convention Center, which made it very easy to stop for a few minutes and get juiced back up. However, between so many panels and events, you just can&amp;#8217;t afford to waste hours waiting for your devices to charge up.&lt;img style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B001Q2FM2W&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/cc_chapman/4448313270/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4002/4448313270_aba7969093.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269298938868&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;Chevy Volt Recharging Station by CC Chapman, on Flickr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I never ran out of battery, although quite a few times I dipped under 10%. My method was to carry a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002SOG4NI?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002SOG4NI&quot;&gt;Griffin PowerDuo&lt;/a&gt;, a backup battery along with its recharging base station - both are small enough to fit in your pants pocket. On the go, the battery pack would keep the iPhone charged up between 95% and 100%. In between panels, I&amp;#8217;d recharge the pack as much as I could. Most rooms do have outlets, so the station made it easy to plug it in and go away without being tethered. If you could stay near the outlet, then its even better - the base station has a USB port which allowed me to charge the iPhone while recharging the battery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001Q2FM2W?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B001Q2FM2W&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/31SSoq04bpL._SL160_.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1269301840619&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another tool at my disposal was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001DQNAJ8?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B001DQNAJ8&quot;&gt;Griffin TuneJuice Charger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B001DQNAJ8&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;which was given out by Groupon at their breakfast event. The charger fits four AA batteries, and while it can&amp;#8217;t recharge them, it allows you to throw as many AAs as you can fit into your backpack, or even buy some extra AAs in an emergency, and charge your iPhone with it. The four included AAs helped me get back to 33% only, which is just about as much as the PowerDuo does as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, since I had my laptop with me most of the time (going against my own tip #1), I would usually keep the iPhone charged by leeching some energy from the USB ports, either during panels, or even while walking around by routing the USB charge cable through the backpack down to my pocket. Geeky? YES.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The laptop would only go down 10% with each full charge of the iPhone, and as I didn&amp;#8217;t use it much, it worked great as a humongous extra battery for the iPhone. That 10% I would get it back quickly by plugging in during panels or in the hallway outlets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Tuck in your badge when leaving the Austin Convention Center&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t walk around town with your SXSW Badge flapping in the wind. Although there are many things that will still give you away as a tourist, you still don&amp;#8217;t want a $700 badge giving you away so quickly. You don&amp;#8217;t want locals rolling their eyes and thinking &amp;#8220;oh, Southby&amp;#8221; whenever you try to venture into town. I would usually tuck it inside my jacket or shirt when leaving the ACC and then getting it out whenever I needed to get back into a badge event.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. Make your reservations three months before SXSW&amp;#8230; or earlier. Or don&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I stayed at the Embassy Suites just across Congress Bridge, which was very convenient as it was just a 10 minute walk to the Austin Convention Center. Even then, next year I will try to nab a room closer to the ACC just for convenience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With that said, the last three days of my stay at Austin were 7 KM away from downtown, in the Comfort Inn at Riverside. I still was able to have a great time, thanks to the R&amp;amp;R shuttles set up for SXSW. Most of the out of town hotels were served by these shuttles, which only cost $40 for a 4/5 day pass. There are two passes: one for Film+Interactive and one for Music. I only needed the latter, because I only went out of town during Music, but if you plan to stay for the whole week out of town you will need to get both passes (totalling $80). The taxi ride would cost you at least $20 each way, so the shuttle is very, very economical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;These shuttles depart every 30 mins or so, which isn&amp;#8217;t too shabby. Oh and one more thing, get a hotel with complimentary breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. Make your schedule&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final dates are not revealed until close to the event, so don&amp;#8217;t even think about coming up with a perfect, down to the minute schedule before the event starts. However, do mark on your schedule which events you do not want to miss at all. The rest of your schedule should revolve around these main events. You may mark which events are interesting for you, and most of these will be going on at the same time. There&amp;#8217;s nothing you can do about that. But at least knowing which events are of interest beforehand will help you when you are going out of one panel and need to know if you should go down four levels, walk to another hotel or take a shuttle for your next panel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ah, keynotes. Be there one hour before the keynote is set to begin, or you will have to go into an overflow room. Might as well stay home watching the livestream in that case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Film screenings: for all but the headliner (KICK ASS) we were able to get into a screening by being there one hour early. KICK ASS had 3,000 people trying to get into a ~300 seat theater. NO. WAY.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And finally, Diggnation Live. We were able to attend it only thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seram.us&quot;&gt;Addis&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; efforts in being there three hours early, in line, and still having about 300 people ahead of us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;6. Love thy taco trucks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Austin has great street fare, which helps a lot when you need to grab a quick bite without dining in in order to hit that next panel in half an hour. ONE TACO set up shop a block away from the convention center, and they had constantly 20 people in line - they&amp;#8217;re that good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will find many street vendors near the convention, just walk around and pick whichever looks good for your taste. Leave the restaurant for dinner, or hit a party with free food (and booze, of course).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;7. Put away your gadgets&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;SXSW is about the people. Don&amp;#8217;t waste your time there looking at Twitter or reading blogs. Use your smartphone to find where people are at with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gowalla.com&quot;&gt;Gowalla&lt;/a&gt;, then go there and TALK to people. Don&amp;#8217;t be That Guy looking at his phone all the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;8. Venture out of SXSW&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There will still be many badge-less events going on around town. Most of the official Interactive parties are not that great, so be on the lookout for unofficial popup events. This year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://garyvaynerchuk.com/&quot;&gt;Gary Vaynerchuk&lt;/a&gt; threw a secret wine party and only revealed the location 10 minutes before it started. I found out about a Lean startup meetup from someone who wasn&amp;#8217;t attending SXSW, and that event was more eye opening than most of the panels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last day in Austin, I didn&amp;#8217;t go to any film screening. I just walked all over Sixth Street, taking it all in. I had as much fun that day as some of the official SXSW Interactive days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;9. Go local&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Austin is very resistant to corporate invasion, and as such is full of small businesses. I saw so many diverse, unique and special restaurants and coffeeshops all throughout the city. Only Starbucks was ever present - you don&amp;#8217;t see lots of national chains in the downtown area. Try to visit as many of these venues, as each will certainly have some special touch that you wish was present in the corporate chains in your town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try the Alamo Drafthouse - these cinemas have great food and beer served during the movie. Go for Torchy&amp;#8217;s Tacos, the best in Austin. Have dessert at Halcyon, after a great dinner at Ranch 616. Drinks at La Condessa, The Gingerman or the Dirty Dog - something for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, visit the Capitol grounds. That&amp;#8217;s the obvious one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;sxsw-mobile-social-bike-0739 by kk+, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/kk/4435232578/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2792/4435232578_97413a6612.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sxsw-mobile-social-bike-0739&quot; width=&quot;333&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Have fun!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You really don&amp;#8217;t have to follow any guidelines. I tried not to overschedule my plans for Austin, and just took it all in as it passed me by. It was an awesome week and look forward to going back in 2011. I hope this little guide helps convince you to join me next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And yes, I promise I will eventually blog about the panels I attended; there is so many to write about, I haven&amp;#8217;t been able to get to it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 80%;&quot;&gt;Note: Amazon links to Griffin chargers are part of the Amazon Affiliate program.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SXSW Day Two - Saturday Morning</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-day-two-saturday-morning"/>
   <updated>2010-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-day-two-saturday-morning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is hard to sit down and write a post with so many events going on all over the city. I&amp;#8217;ll try to do a writeup for each day. Don&amp;#8217;t expect an in depth analysis - we have enough bloggers around here. This is more of a personal record of what I&amp;#8217;ve seen here in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning started with a panel at the Hilton on ActivityStreams, which covered the story of web syndication, through RSS and ATOM and now with the news feed ever so popular in many social websites. The news feed, though, has no common standard; look at FriendFeed, which still has many already dead services under its list of supported sites, but doesn&amp;#8217;t include newer ones. Facebook acquisition aside, it is just too expensive to code up a custom importer for every possible website, with no knowledge of how successful it will be (Should we spend time on supporting this site?).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;ActivityStreams proposes a new set of elements, built on top of ATOM, which is already being adopted by many popular websites even though it is presently only at version 0.8. After going through some philosophy on lifestreams and their complexity, the result is that we can model most news feeds through a simple model: ACTOR + VERB + OBJECT + TARGET. How so? Think about a YouTube video comment you&amp;#8217;ve just made. You are the actor (which is not to say the author, or uploader of the video - although we reuse the author element in ATOM for this), your action is &amp;#8220;commenting&amp;#8221; and object is your comment. The target, finally, is the YouTube video.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;ActivityStreams is used by Google Buzz, and all sites that use it will be supported immediately by Buzz.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;One final comment: Robert Scoble was present, and he livestreamed the session from his laptop to &amp;#8220;The Internets&amp;#8221; (as the panel put it, with a hint of annoyance at the interruption).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that panel, it was off to the Radisson for a panel on the iPad: New Opportunities for Content Creators. The panel was made up of Raven Zachary from small society, Shervin Pishevar, Jason Grigsby and members of mainstream media publications. It was a most interesting panel, covering many new uses of the iPad as seen by the iPhone development community&amp;#8217;s top contenders. This one deserves a whole new post of its own, which I will post later in the week.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SXSW Day One</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-day-one"/>
   <updated>2010-03-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-day-one</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First full day of the South by Southwest Film + Interactive festival&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;is now over. It&amp;#8217;s been more of Interactive rather than Film, as all&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;the panels and activities has just overwhelmed us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We arrived on Thursday to Austin and were able to get to know downtown&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;city thanks to Pablo&amp;#8217;s (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polsense.inc&quot;&gt;http://www.polsense.inc&lt;/a&gt;) previous knowledge of&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;Austin and meeting up with Manuel Rosso. We got a good sense of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;city and the layout and most popular places, which got us all set for&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;Friday&amp;#8217;s SXSW kickoff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Badge pickup was a half hour line or so but organized, you would fill&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;out a card with your info ad after matching it to your my.sxsw profile&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;(which you should have filled out by now) they would quickly print out&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;your badge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The use of location based services I very high in Austin, in part due&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;to it being the homebase of Gowalla, but mostly due to the influx of&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;techies during this weekend. It is a different feeling when you check&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;in anywhere and there&amp;#8217;s 10 to 50 people who&amp;#8217;ve checked in there in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;last 20 minutes. And that&amp;#8217;s just the coffeeshops. Popular SXSW events&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;reach a few hundred. You check in, look to the side and there&amp;#8217;s X from&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;Y company or blog sitting near you, checking in as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And this was just Thursday night before the offcial start of SXSW.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friday morning had no panels yet so we went to the Texas State Capitol&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;grounds. The Capitol building is higher than the D.C. Capitol, I&amp;#8217;m&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;told. Yep, everything is bigger in Texas. The building is beautiful,&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;as well as the grounds. Walking back we decided to grab lunch from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;ONE TACO truck near the Austin Convention Center. We ran into the guys&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;from Gowalla, and their Gowalla MINI Clubman. They are a cool bunch,&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;and we are big fans of their applications so it was very nice to meet&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;almost the whole team in person. The ONETACO tacos are tasty, by the&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;way, especially the bacon loaded Gowalla taco. Try them!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On to the first panel&amp;#8230; We all split up, hitting the SXSW intro&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;(Addis), History of the Button (Pablo) and Beauty in Web Design&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;(myself). Afterwards it was the Chasing Virtual Goods panel by Josh&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;Williams, CEO of Gowalla, where we caught up again with the Gowalla&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;peeps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last panel of the day was Mark Cuban vs Avner of Boxee on the future&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;of streaming video on the TV. It was a very interesting head on&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;discussion until the fire alarm went off and we had to evacuate the&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;convention center. Turned out to be a false alarm, so we could see the&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;end of the debate. It was pretty heated, and myself being a Boxee fan,&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;I found agreeing with Cuban&amp;#8217;s points against the success of a la carte&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;programming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We wanted to see the Kick Ass movie premiere, but we got there and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;line was almost 2,000 people strong. After a while we were told the&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;teather was at capacity so we had to leave. At least we got to see all&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;of the starring actors in person at the red carpet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Got some food, and headed back for the nightlife in downtown Austin.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;There are many, many places, all with their own unique charm. The&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;location based services are great for finding the nearest hot spot and&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;discovering new venues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s about it. One day gone and still one week to go before it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;over. There are a couple neat panels tomorrow and some great events:&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;This Week in Startups Live, Hubble 3D, Diggnation Live. I hope I can&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;make it to all of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll see when I can post again. Typed up all of this on my iPhone&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;thanks to the lack of free Internet access at our suite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And remember, if you&amp;#8217;re here in Austin, follow me: @hectorramos&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>OMGWTFBBQ SXSW!</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/omgwtfbbq-sxsw"/>
   <updated>2010-03-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/omgwtfbbq-sxsw</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Typing from my iPhone a quick pre-flight post. I&amp;#8217;m currently on a&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;plane, departing soon towards Austin, Texas, for a week of panels,&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;networking and BBQ. If anyone who reads this is going to be at SXSW, @&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;me! I&amp;#8217;m @hectorramos on Twitter and on Gowalla:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gowalla.com/hramos&quot;&gt;http://www.gowalla.com/hramos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Using Mint as a BPPR customer</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/using-mint-as-bppr-customer"/>
   <updated>2010-03-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/using-mint-as-bppr-customer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2010-03-03 at 2.20.28 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1267640487019&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For almost two years, we&amp;#8217;ve been trying to get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mint.com&quot;&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt; to work with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popular.com&quot;&gt;Banco Popular de Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s accounts. It all began with the migration to the current 3rd generation BPPR version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some background, first. Mint is a personal finance manager that launched at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch.com/2007/09/18/mint-wins-techcrunch40-50000-award/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch40 in 2008&lt;/a&gt;. It helps you keep track of your transactions, set up budgets and receive alerts on your mobile device. It is an excellent tool for budget management, so much in fact that &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2009/09/14/the-value-of-techcrunch50-mint-acquired-by-intuit-for-170m-two-years-after-winning-tc40/&quot;&gt;Intuit bought it up for $140 million last fall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To work with your transactions, Mint needs access to your online banking website.&amp;nbsp;Mint employs the services of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yodlee.com&quot;&gt;Yodlee&lt;/a&gt; to aggregate all of your accounts. What Yodlee does is abstract the process of scraping your online banking website, providing a single API for Mint and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blippy.com&quot;&gt;other customers&lt;/a&gt;. Yodlee has a database of the most popular online banking sites, their URLs, and their login process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202010-03-03%20at%202.37.04%20PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1267641600141&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the problem seems to have appeared when BPPR started using multitiered authentication. A weird&amp;nbsp;occurrence, since&amp;nbsp;Yodlee and PassMark (now RSA, providers of multitier authentication to many banks) have a &amp;#8216;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.highbeam.com/doc/1G1-128053528.html&quot;&gt;strategic alliance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217; which should help them deal with these types of logins. It was not showing all of the security questions available to BPPR customers. It seemed to be in part due to BPPR&amp;#8217;s use of both English and Spanish security questions. I won&amp;#8217;t go into any more detail - what I am discussing is pretty obvious for the savvy user, but I get a feeling that most executives would not like it if I went into a detailed account of how the authentication system works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;javascript:showFullImage('/display/ShowImage?imageUrl=%2Fstorage%2Fpost-images%2FScreen%20shot%202010-03-03%20at%202.23.01%20PM.png%3F__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION%3D1267640682268',341,553);&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full-image-inline ssNonEditable&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-5992265-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1267640685179&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;After some back and forth with Mint and later Yodlee, it seems like it is finally working. Please note that I am speaking from my personal point of view, and you should wait for any official statement from BPPR. In the meantime, I will share various tips that might help you link your BPPR account with Mint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;When adding your account, please make sure to select &amp;#8220;Popular (PR)&amp;#8221; as your bank.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;You must have had set up your security questions in Spanish. The way BPPR works, it will always ask your question in your initial preferred language. Even though you can switch languages for the website on the fly, this does not apply to the security questions at the moment. I expect this to be changed soon to fully support Mint, but don&amp;#8217;t quote me on that.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why Spanish? Because Yodlee still has an incomplete set of questions available, and it seems like the only valid set of questions that will match in both Mint and BPPR are in Spanish. The questions that worked for me were:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;iquest;Como se llamaba tu primera mascota?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;iquest;Cual era el nombre de tu escuela superior?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;iquest;Cual es el nombre de tu abuelo por parte de padre?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some users report that using the same answer for all security questions helped them. It should still work with different answers to each question, but perhaps this can also help if your questions were set up in English initially. Your mileage may vary.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-5992289-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1267640723081&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it. Please discuss which methods worked and which didn&amp;#8217;t, as we collect all these tips and get nearer to having Mint available for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: Blippy.com doesn&amp;#8217;t work as of this writing, even though I think they use Yodlee, too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The day Quake shook me into programming</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/day-quake-shook-me-into-programming"/>
   <updated>2010-02-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/day-quake-shook-me-into-programming</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/post-images%2Fquake.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-5905637-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1267103565248&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday saw the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bethblog.com/index.php/2010/02/24/the-day-quake-shook-the-gaming-world-carmack-et-al-share-their-qtest-memories/&quot;&gt;14 year anniversary of QTest&amp;#8217;s release&lt;/a&gt;. I still remember that day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was a 12 year old video game lover who used to tinker with computers at school but had only just got my own PC a few months before. Computer games caught my eye, since for the first time I might be able to program my own game. I had this realization when a friend showed me Doom and how he would load it up with modified levels and sprites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Doom mod community was mature and daunting for a 12 year old who had only just discovered it. The arrival of &lt;a href=&quot;http://quake.wikia.com/wiki/Qtest&quot;&gt;QTest&lt;/a&gt; meant that I would be able to be there from the start. I got it from Tucows, probably, and proceeded to play for hours. This was the game I would learn to program and mold to my own idea of the perfect video game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Quake was released and the mods started to appear all over the net. Programming for Quake was pretty easy - the language was called &lt;a href=&quot;http://planetquake.gamespy.com/captured&quot;&gt;Quake C&lt;/a&gt;. It was the perfect language to learn programming. It was based on C, had the same syntax, but didn&amp;#8217;t have structures or arrays. This made it easy for my pre-teen mind to grasp the basics and kept me from needing to learn data structures too early. I would compile my mods using qcc (the QuakeC Compiler) which I later learnt was a play on gcc as I moved up to C (Quake II dropped QuakeC) and C++ (Half-Life).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recall writing a few tutorials on how to make your weapons fire multiple rockets, which would spin around using trigonometric functions I had just learnt that day in school. I got into 3D modelling and 2D texture mapping. I got into level design and writing specs. I created a website and joined &lt;a href=&quot;http://planetquake.gamespy.com/captured&quot;&gt;Captured.com&lt;/a&gt; as an editor.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I guess you could say that thanks to QTest, I learned how to program in C and C++, learned how to use 3D Studio to create models, learned &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_space_partitioning&quot;&gt;basic computer science concepts&lt;/a&gt; while making game levels, develop pretty good Photoshop skills while texturing all the models. I created a modification for Quake which had my entire high school as the game level, and enemy players looked like the principal. Players were dressed with the school&amp;#8217;s uniform. It was a hit in my high school&amp;#8217;s new LAN, where we would stay after school to have huge 16 player deathmatch skirmishes. The teachers, of course, didn&amp;#8217;t agree with us shooting down other students, then Columbine happened, and my Quake mod was forever deleted. Wish I had backed it up&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fileshack.com/file.x/17307/Quake+Deathmatch+Test+%28QTest%29&quot;&gt;QTest&lt;/a&gt;, I developed interest in everything that led me to study Computer Engineering.&amp;nbsp;Thank you, id Software.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Accessing Buzz Timeline Information</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/accessing-buzz-timeline-information"/>
   <updated>2010-02-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/accessing-buzz-timeline-information</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick update regarding the use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://buzz.google.com&quot;&gt;Google Buzz&lt;/a&gt; data that may interest developers.&amp;nbsp;As of today:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can access a user&amp;#8217;s timeline as an &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4287&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; feed using the following URL&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://buzz.googleapis.com/feeds/{user}/public/posted&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is just one user&amp;#8217;s updates, NOT what the user sees in Buzz. You will get a stream of updates, or Buzzes, authored by {user}.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If one were to develop a Buzz client, one would actually need the whole of the timeline seen by the user inside the Buzz tab in Gmail.&amp;nbsp;At the moment there is no one central place where a developer can fetch the Buzz timeline for all the people you follow.&amp;nbsp;However, you may use Contacts access and then iterate through each contact&amp;#8217;s public atom feed, and integrate that into your client.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This, however, is not as useful because you don&amp;#8217;t have access to Groups and so on. It is a good temporary solution, but Google should have the API soon. Probably faster than you can code a good, stable scraping solution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is why you won&amp;#8217;t see native Buzz clients soon. Whomever does that will have a hell of a problem maintaining their custom scraping code. Some people have started their own &lt;a href=&quot;http://allurbuzz.appspot.com/&quot;&gt;firehose scraping projects&lt;/a&gt; already.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Google shall soon (weeks, months) release a proper API with oAuth. That&amp;#8217;s when the barrage of iPhone + iPad apps will arrive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are ways to publish data to your own timeline. To do so requires the setup of a service feed that must be linked by the user in their Google profile. Using&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pubsubhubbub/&quot;&gt;PubSubHubbub&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;the Buzz will appear almost immediately. This is not the equivalent, though, of authoring new Buzzes from a simple mobile client, as the user still needs to associate their profile with the service - a kind of temporary solution while Google finishes their oAuth implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What's all the Buzz about at Google?</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/what-all-buzz-about-at-google"/>
   <updated>2010-02-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/what-all-buzz-about-at-google</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google is launching a new service today, which seems to be a big foray into the social arena, an area where they have been historically lacking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know much about what&amp;#8217;s coming, but it seems like we will all know within the hour. I can only guess that the name of the new product shall be &amp;#8220;Google Buzz&amp;#8221; if I go by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/hectorramos/status/8863611108&quot;&gt;Scoble&amp;#8217;s tweets&lt;/a&gt; and MG Siegler&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2010/02/09/google-buzz-event/&quot;&gt;Tech Crunch article&lt;/a&gt;. They all seem to be dancing around the &amp;#8220;buzz&amp;#8221; while trying to avoid to break their NDAs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/feb0910googleevent&quot;&gt;the event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Need an iPhone App?</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/need-iphone-app"/>
   <updated>2010-02-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/need-iphone-app</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finding out what it takes to develop an iPhone app is a&amp;nbsp;lengthy&amp;nbsp;process - first an idea needs to be developed into a sound design, resources need to fit the development schedule, and deadlines need to be met. However, before we go through all these steps, we first need to establish a &lt;a href=&quot;/request-quote/&quot;&gt;business relationship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a trend where I am usually contacted by an idea person - someone who has a general idea of what an &amp;#8220;awesome&amp;#8221; iPhone application would be like, all they need is for me to develop it and retain 50% or less of the profits. If this fits you, I&amp;#8217;m sorry to say I am not the developer you&amp;#8217;re looking for. This is a high risk situation which does not benefit me. Really, do the math. There is a small chance of the application making it big. If it fails, I&amp;#8217;ve just lost weeks of development time and you&amp;#8217;ve lost nothing. If it works, you&amp;#8217;re sharing in 50% of the profits without having done much at all - ideas are nothing, execution is everything. I&amp;#8217;d rather use my free time to develop my own, just-for-fun &lt;a href=&quot;/apps/&quot;&gt;iPhone apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re still reading this and think that you could work with me on an iPhone application, great! Please &lt;a href=&quot;/request-quote/&quot;&gt;request a quote&lt;/a&gt;. The form will allow me to have a better idea of what you need to be developed. The complexity of the application will help me determine if I should reach out to trusted iPhone developers or if the application can be executed by just a single developer. It also helps me let you know quickly how much it is going to cost to develop the application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developing an iPhone application is not cheap. The development costs cover equipment, utilities, office space and salaries. Also, some features such as Push Notifications carry a recurring cost. I hope that establishing a formal &lt;a href=&quot;/request-quote/&quot;&gt;application development request for&lt;/a&gt;m will help everybody meet their expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LA X</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/la-x"/>
   <updated>2010-02-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/la-x</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/tumblr_krofk4GeKE1qz6kbro1_500.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1265234149295&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, this is the mandatory &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lost_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;LOST&lt;/a&gt; post. If you are no fan of the show, or you haven&amp;#8217;t watched the Season 6 Premier, then I recommend skipping this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;LA X. Title for the Season Six Premiere. Sure, LAX is the airport code for Los Angeles International Airport, but as always, titles have a deeper meaning. What is that meaning? No one knows for sure, but it might be closely related to the divergent timeline that we are observing in this new and final season.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Carlton and Damon would like you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://popwatch.ew.com/2010/02/02/lost-premiere-damon-carlton/&quot;&gt;believe&lt;/a&gt; that these are sideflashes - we are seeing what would have happened had the LOSTies not crashed into the Island. Or that we may be experiencing a fork in time, where the cat is &lt;a href=&quot;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schr&amp;ouml;dinger's_cat&quot;&gt;both dead and alive&lt;/a&gt;. But this is LOST. You haven&amp;#8217;t forgotten Season 3&amp;#8217;s finale, have you? We thought we were seeing Jack&amp;#8217;s flashback, which turned out to be a flashforward to 2007. Season 4 showed us how the Oceanic Six were living after being rescued while&amp;nbsp;simultaneously showing how they ended up being rescued.&amp;nbsp;What if there are no forked timelines? What if&amp;#8230; we are seeing the epilogue, the actual ending of the show, right now as the season progresses? Calling it: Jack will get his neck hurt during the Season Six finale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;There are various differences that might point to that possibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hurley is the luckiest man alive.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rose comforted Jack&amp;#8217;s fear after the turbulence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charlie is alive, thanks to Jack and possibly thanks to the rehab program he would be taken into now that the authorities have arrested him.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sawyer is nice and friendly.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shannon is alive and well in Australia.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Christian Shephard&amp;#8217;s body has disappeared, along with Locke&amp;#8217;s knives.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember the sunken LOST island? Other than a nod to the Atlantis theme, we see that New Otherton was constructed before the island was sunk. This points to the fact that the Jughead was not that which sunk the island. The island must have sunk sometime after the whole Jacob vs Smoke Monster conflict that is now going on in 2007 on the unsunken island - we will see that happen at the end of this season. Or I could be wrong, and the island simply sunk when it was moved by Ben - unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Desmond. Don&amp;#8217;t forget that Desmond has been dislodged from time before - the flashes before his eyes, going to 1996 and back. If the timeline has forked - and remember, there is no alternate timeline as there is no real timeline - then Desmond can flash between both timelines. That is why he is one moment in the plane, and the next he has disappeared. This fits even if the LAX LOSTies are living out the epilogue of the story. Thinking of time as a spiral, with a skipping needle as Faraday described it, Desmond is the needle going from one track to the other in this spinning disc of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Enough time travel. Jacob&amp;#8217;s Nemesis is the Smoke Monster. A force of evil that seems to be contained within the island, constrained by rules which keep it from harming Jacob directly. But wait - Jacob&amp;#8217;s people live at the Temple, the Temple which&amp;#8217;s walls are home to the Smoke Monster? Why weren&amp;#8217;t Jacob&amp;#8217;s people afraid of the Smoke Monster before?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, Ben said these walls are far away from the Temple itself. Still, maybe they were equally protected by the rules, rules which were broken once the Nemesis found a loophole which got Jacob killed. That is why they run and scamper to get the ash around the temple to keep Nemesis out. What about the flare?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does the Smoke Monster need a body to assume a new identity? We&amp;#8217;ve seen Yemi&amp;#8217;s body disappear before, along with Christian&amp;#8217;s. But Locke&amp;#8217;s body is there. Did the bodies get disposed by the Smoke Monster in order to keep up its disguise? Was Locke&amp;#8217;s body simply out of reach and that is why he was discovered?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Was Christian the Smoke Monster in disguise? If so, it seems that the Smoke Monster, through its apparent mind reading, can also imprint it&amp;#8217;s vessel&amp;#8217;s personality. That is why we see traces of Christian and Locke in these manifestations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Was the ash around Jacob&amp;#8217;s cabin actually to keep Nemesis out while Jacob relaxed? But if they can&amp;#8217;t hurt each other, why would Jacob need it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sayid - is he the new vessel for Jacob, the result of a loophole within a loophole, set in place by Jacob in case of Nemesis finding a way to kill him?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Questions were answered. More questions were created. This is why I love LOST so much.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Developers LOVE the iPad</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/developers-love-ipad"/>
   <updated>2010-01-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/developers-love-ipad</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/ipadlove.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1265145654534&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all the disappointment brewing around the iPad announcement, I had to offset it with some praise in my headline, so please excuse me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much has been talked about why the iPad has failed to meet expectations. How much of this was artificially inflated by hype, and how much the iPad did fail to deliver, that&amp;rsquo;s a subject best left to the tech pundits. With that said, allow me to make a case for why the iPad is great news for iPhone developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A big iPod Touch?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll tackle the biggest complaint I&amp;rsquo;ve seen: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s just a big iPod Touch!&amp;rdquo; At a first glance, this seems like an understandable assertion. Users don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily care about the internals, rightfully so, and as such a superficial analysis of what has been presented can be summarized as an iPod Touch in a 9.7&amp;rdquo; screen. &amp;nbsp;What you don&amp;rsquo;t notice, however, is that the underlying iPhone OS has been &lt;em&gt;neatly&lt;/em&gt; packaged as the perfect OS for a multitouch tablet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think about it for a minute &amp;ndash; what would happen if Apple had chosen to go with Mac OS X on the iPad? OS X is &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;designed as a touch oriented interface. Yes, it supports multitouch gestures through the use of the surfaces on the MacBooks and Magic Mouse, but you are not working &lt;em&gt;over&lt;/em&gt; the graphical interface. Doing so would bring up all the issues around this &amp;ndash; the interface is obscured by the input device (a user&amp;rsquo;s fingers in this case), and in doing so, the accuracy is decreased (which is why Touch interfaces go for big interface elements that are easy to interact with).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that I would LOVE to be able to run my OS X apps on the iPad. I don&amp;rsquo;t want a desktop with a menubar and window management, but having the ability to launch OS X apps in a fullscreen frame would be really useful. Existing iPhone apps not converted for the iPad can be used in this fashion, but this is not as big as a problem as iPad applications are based on an expanded iPhone OS. However running the whole kernel and drivers of a full OS X install is not something that can be seamlessly integrated into the iPhone OS&amp;nbsp; &amp;ndash; I bet engineers would rather prefer to run OS X fully as any other tablet does with Windows and Linux and &amp;lt;insert your favorite OS&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you want a touch oriented OS, and with that you will want a good library of touch oriented apps. With the App Store already clocking in at over 140,000 native apps, it is a no brainer that the iPad just &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to be able to run iPhone apps. This is why the iPad is running an improved iPhone OS and not OS X.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enough about the OS &amp;ndash; where is the multitasking!?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahh, multitasking. This subject is not so much about the iPad but about mobile devices in general. Multitasking on a mobile device is tricky &amp;ndash; resources are scarce, and when combined with a phone, no application should ever keep the device from being able to make a call or receive one. You don&amp;rsquo;t want your phone to be crashing while trying to make an emergency call. I think this is the best way to argue against multitasking in the iPhone &amp;ndash; as a new platform, and as much as people don&amp;rsquo;t like Apple&amp;rsquo;s babysitting, developers just couldn&amp;rsquo;t be given full access to multitask. The App Store would be full of such apps, and everybody&amp;rsquo;s iPhone (and by everybody, I mean casual users who know nothing about memory management and resource allocation) would be grinding to a halt as applications fight over which one gets to use the most CPU cycles. Truth is, most developers are not used to multithreading and making good use of a scheduler or thread pool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;By doing this, Apple has helped to foster a healthy application environment in the App Store. &amp;nbsp;Have you played around with a jailbroken iPhone with background applications enabled? Sure, done the right way, it is stable enough, but you&amp;rsquo;ll see many users talking about how the apps crash or don&amp;rsquo;t work correctly. And then they blame Apple for being unable to implement multitasking properly on the iPhone. News flash &amp;ndash; Apple does multitasking quite well with the iPod app, it&amp;rsquo;s the specific app developers who are not making good use of multitasking. And why should they? It&amp;rsquo;s not officially supported by the SDK at this moment, so don&amp;rsquo;t blame them either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Side note &amp;ndash; you may think the iPod app is just playing background music, but iPhone developers who&amp;rsquo;ve worked with multimedia on the iPhone will appreciate the iPhone OS&amp;rsquo;s handling of audio profiles while running multiple apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that Apple could have provided a good way to hook into multitasking properly on the SDK. In fact, I think this is the direction they are heading. Maybe it will be available in iPhone OS 4.0, maybe not. But I think we should have this conversation again when iPhone OS 4.0 is unveiled, as it seems like iPhone OS 3.2 SDK is just a preliminary release of OS 4.0 and a way of demoing the iPad without giving all the iPhone OS 4.0 secrets away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what about multitasking in the current iPhone OS 3.x environment? It works &lt;em&gt;quite well.&lt;/em&gt; Apple encourages developers to be mindful of state in their applications. When the user hits that Home button, the application is sent a notification. The developer is encouraged to handle that notification and save the current state, so that it may be restored the next time the application is launched. &lt;em&gt;The best use of this functionality is beautifully demonstrated by Tweetie 2.&lt;/em&gt; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter on which screen you are, if you quit Tweetie 2, you can be sure that you will get back to the screen the next time you launch it. Save for a few edge cases, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is how Safari works, too. You don&amp;rsquo;t lose the website you were browsing when you hit the Home button, do you? The fact that only one application is visible at a time seems to throw most people off. Remember, iPhone OS 3.0 introduced Push Notifications. Used properly, you do not need any Twitter application to run in the background &amp;ndash; better yet, a server is taking care of the load! Your iPhone is free to dedicate most of its resources to the application that you, as the user, have told it to be the focus of your attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back to the iPad. The new iPhone OS 3.2 introduces popup notifications, which aside from being a good use of screen real estate (they convey detailed information, but easily dismiss by tapping anywhere else), I think popup notifications open the door to managed push notifications. A big gripe about push notifications is that many of them will arrive at once and it usually is a pain to go through all of them without losing some information. Popup notifications may actually be used to handle multiple simultaneous push notifications, but we may have to wait until further iPhone OS 3.2 SDK betas or 4.0 SDK are released.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More inches is usually a good thing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just mentioned screen real estate. This is very, very important for iPhone developers turned into iPad developers. No longer are applications restricted to a small window of 320 pixels by 480 pixels. Now you have a big screen where lots of detailed data can be conveyed to the user. All the drill down table based views of the iPhone can now be replaced by split column views with popup notifications. I am really looking forward to how iPhone application designers will express their newfound freedom and creativity in this expanded screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;One last thing about multitasking: a good example used in favor of multitasking is being able to listen to Pandora while working on other apps. I agree &amp;ndash; I would love to use streaming services more, while using other applications, instead of just relying on streaming music applications just running full screen. Ah, but remember, Apple acquired Lala late last year. I am hoping that whatever Apple decides to do with Lala and its streaming music service, that it will be integrated into the iPod application, therefore allowing for streaming music while using other applications even without proper multitasking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To finish off, another big gripe about the iPad has been the lack of Flash support. I think this issue is best left for a post of its own, as it is not specific to the iPad. I&amp;rsquo;d rather write about how Flash and HTML5 are being used and how it impacts all mobile devices, be them iPhone, Android or WebOS based, even when these mobile devices may support Flash eventually. I&amp;rsquo;ll write about this issue soon, I hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot left to say about the iPad. Why not go at it in the comments?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Apple Tablet: iPad</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/apple-tablet-ipad"/>
   <updated>2010-01-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/apple-tablet-ipad</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/dimensions_20100127.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1265138126380&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exciting day! Apple finally unveiled their latest product:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipad/&quot;&gt;the iPad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It runs iPhone OS 3.2 *at the moment*, although I&amp;rsquo;m sure it will see iPhone OS 4.0 at its release due to the amount of changes to support iPhone and iPad applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gone over the new SDK already, like what I&amp;rsquo;m seeing, and of course I am announcing an update to my bio: I&amp;rsquo;m now an iPad Developer, as well. :D&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SXSW 2010</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-2010"/>
   <updated>2010-01-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/sxsw-2010</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/sxsw.PNG?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1265297512452&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, just dropping by quickly to let everybody know that I will be going to this year&amp;#8217;s SXSW in Austin, TX. This is going to be my first time there, so let me know if you are going to be there!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Loma del Sol Video With Animoto</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/loma-del-sol-video-with-animoto"/>
   <updated>2010-01-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/loma-del-sol-video-with-animoto</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a short video which covers my recent trip to a mountain villa in Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://wanimoto.clearspring.com/o/46928cc51133af17/4b494de91c6ca9d3/46928cc51133af17/65b3c55b/-cpid/99a31d5eceac09ae/-EMH/240/-EMW/432/widget.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was made using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.animoto.com&quot;&gt;Animoto&lt;/a&gt;, an awesome online service which takes your pictures and videos and creates a professional looking video. It costs $3 per full length video, or $30 for a year of unlimited full length videos. You can try it out for free (limited to 30 second videos); this is a short video about my trip to Mayag&amp;uuml;ez:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://wanimoto.clearspring.com/o/46928cc51133af17/4b494eee5ba52013/46928cc51133af17/6728d5d1/-cpid/1252506958bd7c67/-EMH/240/-EMW/432/widget.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I upgraded to an All Access account, in part due to the great quality of the videos and also thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ckorhonen&quot;&gt;Chris Korhonen &lt;/a&gt;from Animoto, who quickly responded to a small rendering issue I had with the Loma Sol video. Their excellent support helped to finalize my decision to pay for the All Access service.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gowalla Hunt</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/gowalla-hunt"/>
   <updated>2009-11-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/gowalla-hunt</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/hectorramos&quot;&gt;follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; you might have noticed all the check ins I&amp;#8217;ve been making through a neat geolocation service called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gowalla.com&quot;&gt;Gowalla&lt;/a&gt;. This service allows you to selectively share your current location with your Gowalla (and Twitter and Facebook) friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 100px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/logo-footer.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1259282492339&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;What makes it different from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brightkite.com&quot;&gt;BrightKite&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://foursquare.com/&quot;&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt; is the great attention to detail and design in the application, from its featured icons all the way to the items you can collect throughout your travels. Also, as opposed to Foursquare, it is available in Puerto Rico and any city worldwide. Not only is the content creation in the hands of the Gowalla team, users can create their own spots. Any Gowalla user can drive up to a venue and register it with the service. The team is open to user feedback, as you may suggest spots that could be promoted to the Featured section. One such example is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/spots/109899&quot;&gt;Castillo San Felipe del Morro&lt;/a&gt; in San Juan, Puerto Rico, which was just added this week.&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/109899-471f93a8167f8ed4c279b9c3cbce073e.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1259283322425&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I had the opportunity to meet &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/sanlei&quot;&gt;Sandi Weldon&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://alamofire.com/&quot;&gt;Alamofire&lt;/a&gt;, the Austin startup behind Gowalla, in an improvised Gowalla meetup with other passionate users. She handed out some neat Gowalla swag that I want to pass on to you. I thought that the best way to do so would be to demonstrate the social geolocation aspect of Gowalla while doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To kick off this game, we&amp;#8217;ll start with a cool Gowalla sticker. You want it? Then you should check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://gowalla.com/users/hramos&quot;&gt;Gowalla profile&lt;/a&gt;, look at the places I&amp;#8217;ve been this week and figure out where I could have had hidden the sticker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a hint:&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3374460-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1259282233575&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you think you know where the Gowalla sticker is? I&amp;#8217;d like to hear from you - did you find the sticker? Did a Gowalla user beat you to it? (Check the People tab at that spot!) You can find me at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/hectorramos&quot;&gt;@hectorramos&lt;/a&gt; (or write to gowalla [at] hectorramos.com). Keep Gowallaing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/photo%202.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3374492-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1259282294135&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Gowalla is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itunes.com/app/Gowalla&quot;&gt;available for the iPhone in the AppStore&lt;/a&gt;. You can also use Gowalla on your Android, iPod Touch or webkit geoenabled mobile device of choice through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://m.gowalla.com&quot;&gt;mobile website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Explosion in Puerto Rico</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/explosion-in-puerto-rico"/>
   <updated>2009-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/explosion-in-puerto-rico</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%2520shot%25202009-10-23%2520at%25201.11.23%2520AM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-4532563-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256277024354&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A huge explosion was felt across the San Juan Metro Area in Puerto Rico around 12:25AM EST. Myself, I woke up thinking someone had broken into my house. However, I live 10 miles or so away from the apparent epicenter. People closer to the San Juan, Bayamon and Guaynabo area report feeling a whooshing sound or sonic boom, followed by shaking. Windows have broken near the explosion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Story is still developing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23ExplosionPR&quot;&gt;Search for #ExplosionPR in Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, which for 10 or 15 minutes was the only source of news. At the moment, Red96 is on the scene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/IWKZ2On7iDs&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/IWKZ2On7iDs&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gallery: &lt;a href=&quot;http://eldifusor.posterous.com/galeria-de-fotos-ciudadanas-sobre-la-explosio&quot;&gt;http://eldifusor.posterous.com/galeria-de-fotos-ciudadanas-sobre-la-explosio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;More being posted at &lt;a href=&quot;http://eldifusor.posterous.com&quot;&gt;http://eldifusor.posterous.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://paropr.posterous.com&quot;&gt;http://paropr.posterous.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Cheapskate's Monitor Stand</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/cheapskate-monitor-stand"/>
   <updated>2009-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/cheapskate-monitor-stand</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/banner.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256186773301&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m always looking for ways of improving my workspace. Being a tall guy, I prefer to use the desk surface to place the keyboard and mouse, instead of using a keyboard tray. However, this places the monitor a few inches below eye level. So for a long time, I have been using two or three thick books to prop up the monitor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why didn&amp;#8217;t I get a monitor stand? Well, most of them are $30 or $40 at least, and they still are no more than 10&amp;#8221; wide or so. This is actually annoying, as I can&amp;#8217;t push the keyboard or mouse underneath, which is the most comfortable position for me. Then I saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://ikeahacker.blogspot.com/2008/12/tv-shelf-with-door-stoppers-for-legs.html&quot;&gt;this post at IKEA Hacker&lt;/a&gt; with instructions on how to create a stand using cheap hardware and decided I would do the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ten months later, I finally set out to Home Depot. I knew I needed a roughly 36&amp;#8221; by 8&amp;#8221; shelf, and around 4&amp;#8221; of lift. I found a black shelf with similar dimensions, and got four 3&amp;#8221; door stops. All for under $15:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_5088.JPG?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256181293790&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Black Shelf: 8.28&lt;br /&gt; Doorstop (4@1.71): 6.84&lt;br /&gt; Total: $13.82&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To build this, you&amp;#8217;ll need a drill, a 3/32&amp;#8221; drillbit (might vary, check your doorstopper&amp;#8217;s dimensions), a ruler and a pencil to mark off the locations for the door stops. If you haven&amp;#8217;t figured it out by now, the door stops will serve as the legs of this monitor stand. Why? They provide the lift I need, without occupying too much desktop area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_5086.JPG?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256186800247&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;You can do this by yourself, certainly. However, I had someone help me with the measurements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/helper.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256186819867&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For these door stops, which are roughly an inch wide, I measured 0.5&amp;#8221; from each edge and marked it off. You might want to try 1&amp;#8221;, but don&amp;#8217;t over do it or you will end up with an unstable stand. Once you have the spot marked, get your 3/32&amp;#8221; bit and drill a guide, a little over halfway in - just make sure it does not go out the other side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_5094.JPG?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256186838659&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then you will want to take one of the door stops, and screw it in by hand. Really, if you don&amp;#8217;t know how to screw this into the hole, you have a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_5095.JPG?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256186861860&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, you might need a little help to finish screwing it in. Just get some pliers and tighten them up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_5099.JPG?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256186882400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Repeat for all for corners, flip and place on your desk. New monitor stand!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_5100.JPG?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1256186938972&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It feels pretty good, gives me enough height and I can comfortably push the keyboard and mouse around without hitting anything. I might get a fifth door stop because it is sagging a little in the middle, but so far it seems like it will hold up. That&amp;#8217;s it! Soon, I&amp;#8217;ll show you how to build your own desk out of a door and some height adjustable legs. First, I need to build it, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Citizen Journalism: Strike in Puerto Rico</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/citizen-journalism-strike-in-puerto"/>
   <updated>2009-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/citizen-journalism-strike-in-puerto</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today a protest is being held in the capital of Puerto Rico, San Juan. It has become an actively discussed topic in Twitter, under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hashtags.org/&quot;&gt;hashtag &lt;/a&gt;#ParoPR.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To aid in the aggregation of the crowdsourced information being spread through Twitter, a small group of citizens have set up a &lt;a href=&quot; http://paropr.posterous.com&quot;&gt;Posterous blog that so far has&amp;nbsp;successfully covered various sides of the ongoing protests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please visit the Posterous blog at &lt;a href=&quot; http://paropr.posterous.com&quot;&gt;http://paropr.posterous.com&lt;/a&gt;. It would also be very helpful to tweet about this event using the hashtag #ParoPR, which could help and spread the word about the ongoing events.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: I created the Posterous blog for ParoPR, however the content is being supplied by a dozen or so contributors from the local Twitter community.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>QUICK TIP: Security Policy Error During Deployment</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/quick-tip-security-policy-error-during"/>
   <updated>2009-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/quick-tip-security-policy-error-during</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I ran into a problem when I tried to deploy my code to my iPhone. I saw the following cryptic message:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Error launching remote program: security policy error.&lt;br /&gt;The program being debugged is not being run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The problem usually shows up for jailbroken devices, but mine is not jailbroken. I solved this problem by deleting all of my expired provisioning profiles. Seems like 3.0 has a problem using the correct profile, and if any expired profile is present it won&amp;#8217;t allow for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now I am having problems deploying to my 3.0.1 iPhone after downgrading from 3.1b5. I had used the symlink Xcode trick, but now it doesn&amp;#8217;t work, even after removing the symlink. Any one in my same position?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Advanced Workshop "Starting and Building a High Growth Venture"</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/advanced-workshop-and-building-high"/>
   <updated>2009-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/advanced-workshop-and-building-high</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend, the CIAPR and Grupo Guayac&amp;aacute;n are hosting an advanced workshop aimed for entrepeneurs, any one who is interested in improving their business or founding one. This is a short adaptation of the Entrepreneurship Development Program from the MIT Sloan School of Management, valued at $8,800.00. This is a great chance to connect and network with local entrepeneurs and investors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guayac&amp;aacute;n is known as the group behind the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enterprizepr.com/Default.aspx?alias=www.enterprizepr.com/grupoguayacan&quot;&gt;EnterpriZe&lt;/a&gt; competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Dates: October 3rd &amp;amp; 4th, 2009&lt;br /&gt; Place: &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=colegio+de+ingenieros&amp;amp;sll=18.430108,-66.060233&amp;amp;sspn=0.011115,0.01929&amp;amp;g=hato+rey,+puerto+rico&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=18.417002,-66.063312&amp;amp;spn=0.002779,0.004823&amp;amp;z=18&amp;amp;iwloc=A&quot;&gt;Colegio de Ingenieros, Hato Rey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* This is a 16 hours general credits workshop for CIAPR members.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;1&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;5&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enterprizepr.com/Default.aspx?alias=www.enterprizepr.com/grupoguayacan&quot;&gt;Grupo Guayac&amp;aacute;n, Inc.&lt;/a&gt; and the &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cms.ciapr2.org/&quot;&gt;Colegio de Ingenieros y Agrimensores de Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; cordially invites you to the Advanced Workshop &amp;#8220;Starting and Building a High Growth Venture&amp;#8221;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;High Growth Venture entrepreneurship is considered a key growth driver for many countries&amp;#8217; economies. Today, engineers and scientists look to generate innovative solutions and technology that could result in an entrepreneurial venture, yet the vast bulk of tech based entrepreneurship initiatives fail.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Understanding the unique challenges and opportunities of tech-based entrepreneurship is essential for converting many of these efforts into real business opportunities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rs6.net/tn.jsp?et=1102722090438&amp;amp;s=1238&amp;amp;e=0016R4WMcpmxn-L-M9kl7fODtCSll9XohjayN2hc6VJWOu-nigBKhjiR-ItNBM5SORvWFFudoQ43rcVgpROOX6hMB19RI9q88DqYneBVKz_qVj-SVbUcG3UMvQ_d43t_N2LbMrN16MwRog=&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View the Program Syllabus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;1&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;123e98d3ef443f18_123e3aa63ec40361_LETTER.BLOCK11&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;5&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration Fee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Early Bird Registration (Due date: September 30th, 2009)&lt;br /&gt;$100.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Regular Registration (After September 30th, 2009)&lt;br /&gt; $115.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rs6.net/tn.jsp?et=1102722090438&amp;amp;s=1238&amp;amp;e=0016R4WMcpmxn__4v5dWru0CkEpNURBSsZ5amFx7sc0WcfeX0uObjP9gQtdOQtGGoRrxxTJNp1ckktf_dTrtgRU_NwTDYFKYRrKvI9jpmq1O9WhKk6uzB7y4qQu_FTt0jmdOiZK8q6yxP8=&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dowload the Registration Form here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;1&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;123e98d3ef443f18_123e3aa63ec40361_LETTER.BLOCK9&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;5&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Saturday - October 3rd: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 8:00 - 9:00&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Registration, breakfast, networking, start building your teams&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9:00 - 10:30&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Introduction:&amp;nbsp; The Economics of Innovation &amp;amp; Entrepreneurship&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; The Entrepreneurial Model: Opportunity Identification &amp;amp; Shaping, Resources, People&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;10:30 - 11:00 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Coffee Break, continue networking - finalize teams&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;11:00 - 12:30&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Identifying and Developing the Opportunity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - Identifying the Customer and their needs&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Developing and defining the compelling Value Proposition&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Validating the Opportunity - Market &amp;amp; Competitive Analysis&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Shaping the Opportunity&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - Disruptive Innovation as the source of huge opportunity &lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Sustaining vs. Disruptive Innovation - &lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Picking the right customer - or &amp;#8220;non - customer&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - Technology as the enabler - not the solution     &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;12:30 - 2:00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Lunch - During lunch the entrepreneurial teams will work together to commence identifying &amp;amp; shaping the business opportunity before them and developing their compelling value proposition.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2:00 - 3:30 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Entrepreneurial Sales &amp;amp; Marketing for High Growth - I&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Market Segmentation - a different approach&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Entry and Growth Strategy - &lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; target markets and sequential market development&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - Competitive advantage &amp;amp; product positioning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3:30 - 4:30&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Coffee Break &amp;amp; Work Session - Teams will continue to develop their opportunity and commence developing a sales &amp;amp; marketing strategy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;4:30 - 6:00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Entrepreneurial Sales &amp;amp; Marketing for High Growth - II&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Sales, Marketing &amp;amp; Distribution for Disruptors&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Strategy and Positioning&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - Advanced topics in Marketing for High Growth &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 6:00 - Whenever!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Teams will further develop their Sales &amp;amp; Marketing Strategy - Market Analysis, Positioning, Initial Target Markets, Growth Strategy &amp;amp; Sales &amp;amp; Marketing Channel Development.&amp;nbsp; Start preparing Power Point Presentations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt; Sunday - October 4th:&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt; 8:00 - 9:00&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Breakfast &amp;amp; Work Session - Refine thoughts and conclusions to date.&amp;nbsp; Incorporate into Power Point Presentations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9.00 - 10:00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Entrepreneurial Leadership &amp;amp; Team  Building&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;10:00 - 10:45&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Coffee Break &amp;amp; Work Session - Teams continue to build and refine presentations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;10:45 - 12:15 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Building and Executing the Business Model&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Characteristics of successful business models&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Shaping business models over time&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - Emergent Strategy &amp;amp; Managing Risk &lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt; 12:15 - 1:30&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lunch &amp;amp; Keynote Speaker&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1:30-3:00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Financing the High Growth Venture&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;  - Facts &amp;amp; fairy tales of new venture financing&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - Challenges and opportunities&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; - Angels, Devils and everything in-between&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt; 3:00 - 3:45&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Coffee Break and Work Session - Finalize Presentation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;3:45 - 5:30&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt; Team Presentations, Judging and Wrap-up&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Threadsy: Unified Inbox for the Web</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/threadsy-unified-inbox-for-web"/>
   <updated>2009-09-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/threadsy-unified-inbox-for-web</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3924410907_171bb054b0.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1253389768095&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch50.com&quot;&gt;TechCrunch50&lt;/a&gt; event was held in San Francisco for the third year in a row. This conference puts almost 50 startups in the spotlight, giving them six minutes to pitch their business and then get drilled by a panel of celebrities, CEOs and investors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-inline ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 150px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202009-09-19%20at%203.28.24%20PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1253388629569&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the big winner was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redbeacon.com&quot;&gt;RedBeacon&lt;/a&gt;, a service that allows you to locate professionals in a specific city and have your orders fulfilled over the web. Another interesting start up was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.citysourced.com/&quot;&gt;CitySourced&lt;/a&gt;, a service that allows city dwellers to report grafitti, crime, potholes and other such problems to their city council as a kind of 311 service. I won&amp;#8217;t go into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.citysourced.com&quot;&gt;CitySourced&lt;/a&gt; now, though, or go through issue of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appsfordemocracy.org/dc-awards-10000-final-prize-to-iphone-facebook-app-combo/&quot;&gt;other Open 311 initiatives&lt;/a&gt; from around the country. I liked CitySourced, they had a great demo and I am looking forward to it being available in my city (fat chance).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202009-09-19%20at%203.51.04%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-4195984-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1253389921175&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.threadsy.com/2009/09/17/threadsy-snags-2nd-place-at-techcrunch-50/&quot;&gt;Second place was awarded to &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.threadsy.com/2009/09/17/threadsy-snags-2nd-place-at-techcrunch-50/&quot;&gt;Threadsy&lt;/a&gt;, and this is what I will be covering today. This company demoed a service that aggregates all your e-mail addresses and social networks into a single inbox. FriendFeed, you say? Not really. Threadsy takes a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You see, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.friendfeed.com&quot;&gt;FriendFeed&lt;/a&gt; lets you subscribe to a person&amp;#8217;s stream, which can be made of a huge collection of blog posts and web services. It feels like an evolution of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, with its greater range of features and conversation tracking; perhaps the main reason it got bought out by Facebook. On the other hand, Threadsy is all about &lt;em&gt;your services&lt;/em&gt;. It aims to create a unified inbox, where no more a friend of yours will wait days or months for a reply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2009-09-19 at 3.10.51 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1253389835313&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever logged into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, only to notice that someone sent you a message four days ago but you never noticed? Sure, you may have seen the Flickr e-mail notice, and perhaps thought you&amp;#8217;d deal with it later. Problem is, that e-mail is now marked as read, you moved on and forgot to log into Flickr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flickr may not be the best example to use, as Threadsy only supports e-mail, Facebook and Twitter at the moment. However, as you can see in the main Threadsy window, my stream is now divided into a inbound and unbound inbox. I can see all my e-mail, from various accounts, on the left, alongside any Twitter DMs, @mentions and Facebook notifications. On the right, I see a combined view of all my Twitter accounts.&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-inline ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202009-09-19%20at%203.12.35%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen%20shot%202009-09-19%20at%203.17.52%20PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1253388004643&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can reply by DM or public @mention using the inbox on the left without any extra effort. Threadsy makes sure that my messages are routed appropiately. This is called the inbound inbox - any message that makes its way here, is something that was sent to you directly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The box on the right, the unbound inbox, displays all messages, regardless of the recipient. Which means that all of your Twitter and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.threadsy.com/2009/09/18/threadsy-adds-facebook-messages-to-your-inbound/&quot;&gt;Facebook stream&lt;/a&gt; will show up here. One feature I really like is that Threadsy fetches the avatar associated with that person&amp;#8217;s profile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-inline ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screen shot 2009-09-19 at 3.35.24 PM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1253388990544&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far I am really liking the interface. Although I prefer to have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atebits.com/tweetie-mac/&quot;&gt;Tweetie&lt;/a&gt; open and use Mail whenever I am on my laptop, I have found that this is the tool to use when I am at work, where it might not be too smart to keep multiple websites open calling for my attention. I only need to have one tab open and periodically check the inbound inbox to see if I have missed anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to Threadsy adding more service integration and this could be a big winner in my book. Will it be profitable? That remains to be seen. FriendFeed allegedly sold for $50 million to Facebook, since it may prove essential in helping Facebook compete with Twitter. However, who would Threadsy benefit?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadsy.com&quot;&gt;Threadsy&lt;/a&gt; and ask for a beta invite if you wish to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: &lt;/em&gt;I forgot to mention that, in a similar manner to FriendFeed, Threadsy does aggregate all of your friend&amp;#8217;s profiles. You can click on a friend and see a list of all their associated profiles for a huge range of services, not only Facebook and Twitter. I do have some issues with it mixing up my friend&amp;#8217;s identities, but this is something I will probably take up privately with the developers and help them debug.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>COM:LINK hits it big in Japan</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/comlink-hits-it-big-in-japan"/>
   <updated>2009-08-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/comlink-hits-it-big-in-japan</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was looking through my usage stats for the week, and noticed a weird 400% bump in the daily COM:LINK downloads. A quick look through my referrers pointed me to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipodtouchlab.com/2009/08/iphone-bluetooth-comlink-443.html&quot;&gt;this article from a Japanese blog&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipodtouchlab.com&quot;&gt;iPhone iPod Touch Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, if you prefer to read the article in English, here is &lt;a href=&quot;http://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=ja&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;u=http://ipodtouchlab.com/2009/08/iphone-bluetooth-comlink-443.html&quot;&gt;a link from Google with a not-so-accurate translation&lt;/a&gt;. The introduction reads (loosely translated back into English):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span onmouseover=&quot;_tipon(this)&quot; onmouseout=&quot;_tipoff()&quot;&gt;Once widely used, the two-way radio is seldom seen on a mobile phone except for business use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span onmouseover=&quot;_tipon(this)&quot; onmouseout=&quot;_tipoff()&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/comlink/&quot;&gt;COM:LINK&lt;/a&gt; for the iPhone\iPod Touch (2G with Bluetooth) uses the new Bluetooth feature to bring you a free application that relives the nostalgia of walkie-talkie communications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=322502765&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/original.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1251433189570&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;It was a nice surprise to see the application covered all the way over in Japan, but much nicer was seeing how the userbase has grown over the last week. We now have more Japanese users than all other countries combined.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the next month an update to &lt;a href=&quot;/comlink/&quot;&gt;COM:LINK&lt;/a&gt; should be arriving which will bring even more sharing features to the&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=322502765&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt; most popular Bluetooth walkie-talkie application in the App Store&lt;/a&gt; (that side of the world, anyway!).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>"Such is life."</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/is-life"/>
   <updated>2009-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/is-life</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That simple statement has created an uproar in Puerto Rico. &amp;#8220;Rivieras del Caribe&amp;#8221;, a proposal to revive the lands given back to Ceiba by the US military, is led by Jaime Gonzalez. Monday, August 24 saw the release of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sOK5dweZEaQ&quot;&gt;video taken mid-July, during which Jaime Gonzalez told Ceiba residents that indeed, the proposal is geared toward tourists and affluent people&lt;/a&gt;, if you can&amp;#8217;t afford the stores, you may go and take a stroll and watch the cruise ships come in. They can also people-watch the rich as they shop! And if you don&amp;#8217;t like it, well, &amp;#8220;such is life.&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The phrase was quickly picked up by the Puerto Rican Twitter community. A common comeback for any kind of whine is, well, &amp;#8220;such is life!&amp;#8221; In honor of the phrase, &lt;a href=&quot;http://redod.com/?p=29&quot;&gt;redod has created a new design to commemorate the life of the rich and affluent&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Sushi-Is-Life-copy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3967237-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1251318228961&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px;&quot;&gt;OK, so inspiration turned the design into a Sushi chef stylization of Jaime Gonzalez, and the phrase might have been changed a little, but hey, such is life!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The design has been uploaded to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cafepress.com/redod&quot;&gt;CafePress&lt;/a&gt;, for the sole enjoyment of those who can afford to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cafepress.com/redod&quot;&gt;buy a T-Shirt&lt;/a&gt;! If you can&amp;#8217;t, well, like redod, says, you may stroll in and look at the designs, you won&amp;#8217;t get charged for that.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>App Store Review Process Woes</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/app-store-review-process-woes"/>
   <updated>2009-08-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/app-store-review-process-woes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/apple-is-growing-rotten-to-the-core-and-its-likely-atts-fault/&quot;&gt;word came out about Apple&amp;#8217;s removal of all Google Voice applications&lt;/a&gt; from the iTunes App Store, the approval process for iPhone applications has come under intense scrutiny. Being an iPhone developer, I would like to share my experience with the application submission process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;All three of my 3.0 iPhone applications have been rejected at one point or another in the review process. Lets start with the less controversial one: ImageShare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/original-4.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1249920575617&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/imageshare&quot;&gt;ImageShare&lt;/a&gt; was quickly coded after the WWDC09 Yerba Buena Bash on Thursday, July 12th, using an iPhone 3G and iPod Touch 2G to test the transmission of data through Bluetooth. The next morning, I sat down with an Apple User Experience engineer to go through the UI. He made a couple of suggestions, which I duly noted and implemented. I submitted the application somewhere around July 16th, only to get a rejection letter around one week later. The reason? Non-standard UI, for the use of a &amp;#8220;Send Image&amp;#8221; function using an Action icon which is normally reserved for UIActionSheet calls (that is the prompt that slides up from the bottom side of the screen). The funny thing is that the Apple engineer was the one to suggest this. I reverted the button to look more like my initial implementation, and over two weeks later my application was finally approved. Total time from initial submission until final approval: 3 and a half weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/original.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1249920639337&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Now, my second application, &lt;a href=&quot;/comlink&quot;&gt;COM:LINK&lt;/a&gt;, also hit a roadblock in the App Store review process. Around a week after initial submission, I get an e-mail from Apple saying that their review might take a little longer than usual. I start to get worried&amp;#8230; until one more week passes by and I get a call from Richard Chipman. You see, the initial name for COM:LINK was actually Spy Radio. He says that the problem with my application is that the Spy in the title might cause negative connotations, and people might believe their conversations are being spied on. Oookay. At least it is not a problem with the way the application uses GKVoiceChat or Bluetooth. He says that since the Spy Radio name is embedded in the graphics, I will have to resubmit the binary, otherwise I could have had just changed the name from within iTunes Connect and it could be approved right away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;#8230; a minor annoyance. I call Alfredo Richner and Pablo L&amp;oacute;pez to discuss what new name we can use for the application. We come up with COM:LINK, Alfredo redoes the graphics and we resubmit the binary three days after Richard&amp;#8217;s call. Well, this time it takes 16 more days of App Store review limbo until COM:LINK is FINALLY approved. Total time spent in the App Store review process due to initial rejection and resubmission: 31 days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/original%201.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1249920746151&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Another of my applications is &lt;a href=&quot;/youtool&quot;&gt;YouTool&lt;/a&gt;. This is a very, very simple application that launches YouTube videos based on the video id that it is given. Very useful if YouTube is blocked on your network. Well, version 1.0 was approved within one or two weeks without any issues. One of the issues people kept bringing up is what happened when a video id was misspelled, usually due to l (lower-case L) and 1 (the number) being easily confused. So YouTool 1.1 now uses Google Data to access the YouTube API and search for the video being launched. That way you can tell if the video id is incorrect, and the user is given the chance to fix it without having to relaunch YouTool. But this is not what got YouTool 1.1 rejected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;An extra feature of YouTool 1.1 is the History section. Any previously launched videos are stored in YouTool and the user can browse this list. The YouTube video title is displayed in this list. And this is what got 1.1 rejected because I didn&amp;#8217;t give it a 17+ rating (it took Apple 14 days to reject it because of this, BTW).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Apple has a point here - any video title could contain cuss words or anything that would violate YouTool&amp;#8217;s previous 4+ rating. What I don&amp;#8217;t agree with on Apple here, is their immediate rejection of the YouTool 1.1 binary. They could have just called, or sent an e-mail, like they&amp;#8217;ve done previously. They could have had asked me to log into iTunes Connect and update the ratings so that they could approve the application. No, they rejected the binary, which means that even though I have already set the 17+ rating for YouTool, now it has to wait 14 more days before being, hopefully, approved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Apps_store.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1249920769725&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Yes, I expect people to say that I got it coming for not taking care of the ratings. However, many developers have been contacted by Apple during the transition to 3.0, in cases where they noticed that applications where not yet rated. They have also contacted other developers so that they could update the ratings. This is something that does not require any changes in the binary!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#8217;s it. These are my three rejection stories. Hopefully this will help other developers avoid going through the same situations.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>COM:LINK - Two Way Bluetooth Walkie Talkie</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/comlink-two-way-bluetooth-walkie-talkie"/>
   <updated>2009-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/comlink-two-way-bluetooth-walkie-talkie</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our latest application, &lt;a href=&quot;/comlink/&quot;&gt;COM:LINK&lt;/a&gt;, is built upon the iPhone&amp;#8217;s new Bluetooth Voice Chat functionality. It allows two friends to chat through their iPhone or iPod Touch using the Bluetooth connection, with out running down their minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, you will need to be within a few hundred feet of each other for the Bluetooth connection to be established. Once paired, two buddies can chat all they want through their COM:LINK radio - organize your own &amp;#8220;secret missions&amp;#8221; for play, or use it in real situations where there is no cell signal coverage - great in San Francisco!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;The decibel meter goes up and down as you speak into the COM:LINK. It works just like a real radio - hold down the Talk Button to chat with your buddy. Mute your speakers to mantain your cover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Availability&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;COM:LINK is &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=322502765&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;now available on the iTunes App Store for FREE!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look for our upcoming COM:LINK companion app which will include extra features.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Share Images From iPhone to iPhone With Bluetooth</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/share-images-from-iphone-to-iphone-with"/>
   <updated>2009-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/share-images-from-iphone-to-iphone-with</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve released a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hectorramos.com/iphone-app-listing/&quot;&gt;new application&lt;/a&gt; for the iPhone and iPod Touch which allows users to send and receive images without the need of a network (cell or Wi-Fi) connection. This is due to the Bluetooth capabilities unlocked by iPhone OS 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/original-4.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1247607034799&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does it work? After pairing both devices by launching &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hectorramos.com/imageshare&quot;&gt;ImageShare&lt;/a&gt;, you can just go ahead and take a new picture or select one from your photo albums. Hit Send, and the image smoothly slides over to the other iPhone or iPod. It is automatically saved to the receiver&amp;#8217;s photo album. That is all there is to it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;itms://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=320375566&amp;amp;mt=8&amp;amp;s=143441&quot;&gt;Download ImageShare on the iTunes App Store today for free.&lt;/a&gt; This is just the first version, lots of features have already been added for v1.1 which should be out next month!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tecnamica Interview with Vaya Broqui</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/tecnamica-interview-with-vaya-broqui"/>
   <updated>2009-07-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/tecnamica-interview-with-vaya-broqui</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tecnamica.com/&quot;&gt;Tecnamica&lt;/a&gt; is a new development in Latin America, covering technology in Spanish. They are distinguishing themselves by creating their own content and producing a weekly podcast covering the hottest news in the tech world. They called us shortly after getting back from WWDC for an interview. It was a very fun afternoon session where we covered everything from the formal WWDC event, to our adventures meeting other developers and the future of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vayabroqui.com&quot;&gt;Vaya Broqui&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tecnamica.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/prueba_3.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1246817978004&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The podcast is now available &lt;a href=&quot;http://tecnamica.com/2009/07/05/podcast-7.aspx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>YouTool: YouTube Video Launcher for your iPhone</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/youtool-youtube-video-launcher-for-your"/>
   <updated>2009-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/youtool-youtube-video-launcher-for-your</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, one of my iPhone applications was released for sale in the iTunes App Store. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hectorramos.com/youtool/&quot;&gt;YouTool&lt;/a&gt; is an application that allows the user to launch a YouTube video without having to search for it through the YouTube iPhone App.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;itms://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=320588383&amp;amp;mt=8&amp;amp;s=143441&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/original%201.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Why would you need this? Well, the app actually arose out of my own need. I developed it earlier this year because at my workplace, YouTube is blocked and I would sometimes receive a link to a YouTube video through e-mail or IM, but I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be able to open it. I would then proceed to either ask my friend for the name of the video so that I could search for it on the iPhone, or I would e-mail myself the link so that I could open it through the iPhone&amp;#8217;s Mail application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the e-mail would not get there fast enough, and I would proceed to laborously type in the whole URL into Safari which would then enable me to watch the video. That&amp;#8217;s when I thought I could make a simple app that asks for the unique YouTube video identifier code and it would take care of forming the whole URL for myself, which I could use to open YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does it work? Let&amp;#8217;s say you receive the following URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EWrPYrIYh5Q&quot;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EWrPYrIYh5Q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notice that string of characters at the end of the URL? Those identify your video uniquely in YouTube&amp;#8217;s system. In this case, EWrPYrIYh5Q is the code for the video you just received. YouTool is an utilty application, so launching it will take you straight to the only screen you will need:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screenshot%2520on%25202009-07-03%2520at%252011.22.12%2520PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3504948-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1246678206151&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tap on the text field and input your video code: EWrPYrIYh5Q&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screenshot%2520on%25202009-07-03%2520at%252011.24.09%2520PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3504951-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1246678223796&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tap Done or the Launch YouTube button to start enjoying your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EWrPYrIYh5Q&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; in the native YouTube iPhone app!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;YouTool has been in my iPhone for months, and was one of the first iPhone applications I developed. It took only 30 minutes to program, and some more to come up with the simple graphics. I never intended on releasing it, but as I kept getting queries from my friends regarding the same YouTube scenario, I decided to polish the app and &lt;a href=&quot;itms://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=320588383&amp;amp;mt=8&amp;amp;s=143441&quot;&gt;release it for free on the iTunes App Store.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>WWDC Demo: Parranda for iPhone and iPod touch</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/wwdc-demo-parranda-for-iphone-and-ipod"/>
   <updated>2009-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/wwdc-demo-parranda-for-iphone-and-ipod</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, during WWDC09, we met up with Victor Agreda, Jr., editor at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tuaw.com/2009/06/26/wwdc-demo-parranda-for-iphone-and-ipod-touch/&quot;&gt;The Unnofficial Apple Weblog&lt;/a&gt;. We demoed the Parranda application for iPhone and iPod touch, and talked about its success in the Puerto Rican market. Here&amp;#8217;s an excerpt from the article:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The enthusiastic developers of Parranda were at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tuaw.com/tag/WWDC/&quot;&gt;WWDC&lt;/a&gt; to show off their app, a simple one-man-band party in your hand. &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=297296714&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Parranda&lt;/a&gt; (iTunes link) has a lot of polish, too, with instruments that aren&amp;#8217;t just one big button, like some &amp;#8220;soundboard&amp;#8221; music apps. The cowbell, for example, allows you to tap on different parts of the instrument, which any decent cowbell player will tell you, creates very different sounds. Mostly. You can zoom in or out on the instruments, something you will have to see in the video, but it is a nice effect and adds to the experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also watch a video of our demo below. Those are my neatly manicured hands holding my previous iPhone 3G while Pablo Lopez goes over the different musical instruments in Parranda:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;505&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/WbhAhkCvRxA&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;rel=0&amp;color1=0x5d1719&amp;color2=0xcd311b&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/WbhAhkCvRxA&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;rel=0&amp;color1=0x5d1719&amp;color2=0xcd311b&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;505&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shortly after this video was recorded, Parranda 2.1 - NuYorican Edition was approved. It introduces the new Parrandator all-in-one instrument, which allows you to create your own parties without switching out instruments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parrandapr.com&quot;&gt;Parranda&lt;/a&gt; was developed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vayabroqui.com&quot;&gt;Vaya Broqui&lt;/a&gt; and is &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=297296714&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;available on the iPhone App Store for $2.99&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=297296714&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://parrandapr.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/app_store_badge_0708_small.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1246057999110&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>iPhone 3G S Obtained!</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/iphone-3g-s-obtained"/>
   <updated>2009-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/iphone-3g-s-obtained</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had to work today, like every friday and the whole week, so I was not sure I&amp;#8217;d be able to snag a new iPhone 3G S before clocking in at work. I went to Plaza Carolina&amp;#8217;s flagship AT&amp;amp;T store at 8AM and luckily there was almost no queue. Fifteen minutes in and out and I&amp;#8217;ve got the new iPhone 3G S 32 GB model in my possession.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had already played with it last week during WWDC, played around with the Compass and so on, but that was under the closeful watch of Apple engineers. Now, after been able to use it a little more, I can really say it is blazing fast. Applications launch much faster, pictures are snapped quickly and look GREAT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tested out Voice Control and it is pretty good. The quality of videos looks OK for an iPhone. Let&amp;#8217;s see how it fares during the next few days&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Enable MMS and Internet Tethering on your iPhone 3.0 with iTunes 8.2</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/enable-mms-and-internet-tethering-on"/>
   <updated>2009-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/enable-mms-and-internet-tethering-on</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve removed all information related to the enabling of Internet Tethering and MMS on your iPhone. I believe the information is sufficiently spread out through the web, and such topic falls out of the scope of my personal website. Additionally, MMS still won&amp;#8217;t work as long as you are on an iPhone Messaging plan - that is, until AT&amp;amp;T officially supports it. Internet Tethering still works, but you shall proceed at your own risk, as your carrier may still charge you for the usage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my Spanish speaking friends, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iphonefanatic.net&quot;&gt;iPhone Fanatic&amp;#8217;s website&lt;/a&gt; for more information on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Parranda Update: NuYorican Edition</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/parranda-update-nuyorican-edition"/>
   <updated>2009-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/parranda-update-nuyorican-edition</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screenshot%2520on%25202009-06-17%2520at%252012.59.07%2520AM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3366790-thumbnail.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1245280753537&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vayabroqui.com/2009/04/01/parranda-puerto-rico/&quot;&gt;Parranda&lt;/a&gt; for the iPhone has been updated to commemorate &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/oquendo/sets/72157619663148579/&quot;&gt;2009&amp;#8217;s Puerto Rican Day Parade in NYC&lt;/a&gt;. This update introduces the Parrandator, a single screen containing most of the instruments so that you can mix it up and create interesting mobile parrandas right on your iPhone or iPod Touch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Parranda is an iPhone and iPod Touch application that contains maracas, panderos, a cencerro, a g&amp;uuml;iro, some palitos and a tromb&amp;oacute;n so that you can throw your own very Puerto Rican parranda anywhere you are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Check it out in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=297296714&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/thumbnails%2F3835484-3374492-thumbnail.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3374497-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 240px;&quot;&gt;The new Parrandator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>WWDC 2009 Attendee Bash: CAKE</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/attendee-bash-cake"/>
   <updated>2009-06-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/attendee-bash-cake</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Screenshot on 2009-06-15 at 10.22.47 AM.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1245086573280&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px;&quot;&gt;That&amp;#8217;s Pablo Lopez and me at the WWDC Attendee Bash. Pablo is the guy in the green jacket, I&amp;#8217;m in the Apple track jacket holding up my camera next to him&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I am back from WWDC. I&amp;#8217;ve got lots of things to write about, I just need to verify what is public and what I cannot discuss just yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the meantime here are a couple of Voice Memo clips taken during the CAKE performance on June 11&amp;#8217;s WWDC Attendee Bash event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Netflix Responds</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/netflix-responds"/>
   <updated>2009-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/netflix-responds</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I received an e-mail from Netflix today. It seems like they want me back as a client!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/comeback.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are even offering me their &lt;strong&gt;instant watch&lt;/strong&gt; feature:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/comebackiw.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3268457-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, as soon as I sign up with them again, they&amp;#8217;ll tell me the feature is not available in Puerto Rico. Even though they keep advertising it when they ask me to come back after I cancelled the service for not being able to use Instant Watch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hey Netflix, I&amp;#8217;m ok with you if studios really do limit your licensing, even if it seems shady that none would include Puerto Rico (the Instant Watch ban is not title-specific, but service-wide). &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But please don&amp;#8217;t try to lure me back with false promises.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Apple Worldwide Developer's Conference</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/apple-worldwide-developer-conference"/>
   <updated>2009-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/apple-worldwide-developer-conference</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is it. I am packing up, as light as possible, to leave in a few hours on a flight to San Francisco. I don&amp;#8217;t expect to post too frequently while spending my week at the WWDC, so the best you can do is follow me on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/hectorramos&quot;&gt;@hectorramos&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;ll be updating constantly once I land in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re attending the WWDC, please give me a shout. I&amp;#8217;ll be arriving around 10 PM on Saturday night.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Netflix Excludes Puerto Rico, Charges Full Price</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/netflix-excludes-puerto-rico-charges"/>
   <updated>2009-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/netflix-excludes-puerto-rico-charges</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know Netflix, right? The online DVD and Blu-Ray Disc rental service that everyone loves. If you&amp;#8217;ve never heard of Netflix, they basically charge you a flat monthly rate and in exchange they will mail you one or more (depending on your plan) movies for you to keep indefinitely. No late fees, no time limits, watch them whenever you want and toss them back in the mail when you are done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/399px-Netflix_Logo.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent idea. I&amp;#8217;ve been using Netflix on and off since the early 2000s, even though their turn over times for Puerto Rico are usually in the three to four day range (as opposed to next day delivery in most US cities). I gladly paid the monthly rate which let me keep up to three movies at any time, and I would rotate through my queue so that I would always have two movies at home while the third one came back from Netflix. There was never a shortage of movies to watch at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then Netflix came up with an even greater idea. Instant Streaming of movies! As part of your membership, with no extra cost, you would be able to stream a limited selection of their movies and watch them on your computer. By the time they came up with this feature, I had placed my account on hiatus as I had been very busy at work and wasn&amp;#8217;t able to watch too many movies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/netflix-branded-xbox-360.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;However, a couple of companies, such as Roku, came up with standalone Netflix streaming devices. These devices allow you to Instant Stream your Netflix movies and watch them on your HDTV, no need to be stuck on your computer chair watching them on a small screen. Then Microsoft released an update to the Xbox 360 which included Instant Streaming support for Netflix members (as long as you also pay the Xbox Live Gold membership fee).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was perfect. I reactivated my subscription to Netflix, which made promises of Instant Streaming anywhere in the USA, anxious to test out this new feature on my Xbox 360. You can guess what happened next - Netflix told me I can not make use of this feature, one which I am paying for as part of my membership, because I live in Puerto Rico. A territory of the United States, not a foreign country! We are US Citizens, use dollars as our currency and of course the USPS handles all of our mail, including the delivery of Netflix discs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was enraged. I contacted them only to be told they only support the 50 states of the United States of America, which does not cover Puerto Rico due to our status as a territory. Great. I pay full price and get a feature cut off, which wouldn&amp;#8217;t cost extra to Netflix considering I am paying for my own bandwidth and they don&amp;#8217;t have to mail anything &amp;#8220;all the way over here&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a work-around, however. The way the Xbox 360 &amp;amp; Roku works with Netflix is by asking for a device code that is used to link your Netflix account to your device. If you would try to generate this device code on your computer while in Puerto Rico, Netflix would deny your request. However, use a proxy or, as in my case, use your iPhone 3G connection, and Netflix will happily generate a device key for you to use. For the longest time, Netflix would not test your device&amp;#8217;s IP to make sure you were still within the 50 United States, so this allowed me to make use of Instant Streaming for six months. It was GREAT, I could watch many movies I would rather not wait for the disc to arrive. I could just browse around and add many rare, unheard of movies and watch then randomly as I wished. Until one Saturday morning, it all &lt;strong&gt;stopped working&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/twitter_logo_header.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I tweeted about the sudden Instant Streaming failure on my Xbox 360. Over the rest of the day, fellow Xbox 360 and Roku owners reported similar results. Netflix had blocked our Instant Streaming work around. Within days, a couple dozen of Puerto Rico Netflix customers had cancelled their service. Most of them where extremely happy with the Netflix disc service, but were disgusted with the differential treatment given to Puerto Rican customers. My girlfriend cancelled the service even though she had never made use of the Instant Streaming feature - the reason, of course, was because Netflix had always blocked the feature from working on your web browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have called out Netflix, seeking answers, and all they&amp;#8217;ve said is that Instant Streaming is not supported outside of the 50 states. They haven&amp;#8217;t addressed the issue of why they are charging us the same price for half the service. Nor have they justified their reasons. Even Hulu, which once blocked Puerto Rico, changed their policy once they realized &lt;strong&gt;Puerto Rico IS PART OF THE UNITED STATES&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Picture%202.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3075799-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I apologize for going on so long on this rant. All I want is for my fellow Puerto Rican Netflix clients to show up and share their stories. Let our voice be heard, my intention is to collect all of these stories and make them public. They can disregard a single user inquiring about their lack of support for Puerto Rico, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;but our combined wallets should make them reconsider. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;If you are a Netflix subscriber in Puerto Rico, please do your part and CANCEL your membership TODAY. You are not getting the full package that you are paying for.&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you cancel Netflix because they don&amp;#8217;t provide Instant Streaming in Puerto Rico? Are you considering doing so? Please share your stories in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;digg_skin = 'compact';&lt;br/&gt;digg_url = 'http://www.hectorramos.com/journal/2009/5/31/netflix-excludes-puerto-rico-charges-full-price.html';&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;script src=&quot;http://digg.com/tools/diggthis.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Getting Ready for WWDC 2009</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/getting-ready-for-wwdc-2009"/>
   <updated>2009-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/getting-ready-for-wwdc-2009</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every year, come summer, Apple hosts the &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/wwdc/&quot;&gt;Worldwide Developer&amp;#8217;s Conference&lt;/a&gt;, a full week of &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/wwdc/sessions/&quot;&gt;seminars and hands-on labs&lt;/a&gt; covering Mac and iPhone development, straight from the Apple engineers themselves. Myself, being a recent Mac convert and a software engineer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/wwdc/experience/&quot;&gt;couldn&amp;#8217;t let this opportunity go by&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As such, &lt;strong&gt;I will be assisting this year&amp;#8217;s WWDC&lt;/strong&gt;, to be held at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moscone.com/&quot;&gt;Moscone West&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco June 8 - June 12.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With little over a week left, I am midway through my preparations for what I expect to be a memorable week. I have never visited San Francisco, although it still stands amongst the top three cities I would like to live in (for a short while, at least). It is the heart of the Web 2.0 explosion and home to numerous startups and entrepeneurs like myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For all those fellow developers which I am hoping I will get to meet soon, the rest of this post will cover my obsessive compulsive over-preparation for the upcoming trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Finding the Right Laptop Bag&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4481.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3212129-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I got my Macbook, I ordered a homemade sleeve from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.etsy.com&quot;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt; as an attempt to give my new machine a unique touch. The sleeve served its purpose and protected the Macbook during its three month stay in a leather briefcase which I hoped would not make me look like a college kid at my workplace. However, it was bulky and stiff and the straps broke loose. So I got myself a Targus checkpoint ready laptop backpack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although I would prefer a messenger bag or something with a single strap that would look less like what something a college kid would carry, I had to consider the trip and the need for lots of storage space plus it had to help me get through the TSA with minimal handling of the laptop itself. The bag is the zipper-through kind, which opens up like a clam and leaves the laptop in just one side, with no metal zippers or accessories below it which hopefully will make it clear enough that it is a laptop when seen through the airport X-ray machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4479.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3212153-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;It has enough pockets to hold my keyboard, mouse, extra power adapter (I have one permanently on my desk, and another in the bag - expensive at $80 a pop, but oh so convenient) and various notebooks and miscellanea which I will get to shortly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bag was purchased at CompUSA - yes, the once defunct company. It was purchased by Systemax and seeing that their Caparra, Puerto Rico location was very profitable, they reopened under the same CompUSA branding. It is an excellent store, nothing like the old CompUSA franchise. Prices are way cheaper than Best Buy, and you can order through their site (Systemax owns TigerDirect.com and CircuitCity.com) and pick it up at the store without paying for shipping, even when they have to order it from their mainland warehouse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;#8217;s In My Laptop Bag?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4473.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3212168-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;As I mentioned already, it holds my Macbook (2009, unibody, 2.4Ghz), the Wireless Apple keyboard and extra charger. I will cover in a future post the whole contents of the bag as the departure date approaches, but I wanted to get to one neat item I found yesterday while shopping at Border&amp;#8217;s in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plazalasamericas.net/&quot;&gt;Plaza las Americas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I bought my first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moleskine.com/&quot;&gt;Moleskine&lt;/a&gt; notebook. But it is no plain notebook - it is actually a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moleskine.com/moleskinecity/cities/san_francisco.php&quot;&gt;San Francisco city guide&lt;/a&gt;! It contains maps of public transportation available in San Francisco (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bart.gov&quot;&gt;BART&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfmta.com/cms/home/sfmta.php&quot;&gt;Muni&lt;/a&gt;). I would describe it as the analog version of my iPhone - when my battery is dead or reception is bad, I can still whip out the notebook and look up my schedule, glance at the maps, or simply add to my travel journal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-left ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4475.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3212202-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;This is the general area I will be in for the whole week. The Moleskine has these transparent sheets that you can lay over any page, allowing you to mark it up without ruining the map. I&amp;#8217;ve marked the Moscone Center and a nearby Apple Store.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4476.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3212237-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;As you can see, it also contains a few tabbed pages where I plan to write down all the suggested places I will want to visit or just keep a log of those I&amp;#8217;ve visited on my trip. I believe this will make for a very unique keepsake of my first trip to San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Checklist&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;No more pictures for now - that&amp;#8217;s for the later post. Meanwhile, here&amp;#8217;s a basic checklist of what I will take with me:&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-float-right ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4484.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Macbook&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;MagSafe Adapter&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;3 feet of white Ethernet cable - got them for cheap on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.monoprice.com&quot;&gt;monoprice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000NK6J6Q?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000NK6J6Q&quot;&gt;Canon PowerShot SD750&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B000NK6J6Q&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mini USB cable for the camera&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015DYMVO?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015DYMVO&quot;&gt;Belkin Mini Surge Protector Dual USB Charger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015DYMVO&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; (share rare power connectors with buddies)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TTMEWO?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000TTMEWO&quot;&gt;Belkin Swivel Hub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B000TTMEWO&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; - swivels for easy access&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001V7XPSA?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B001V7XPSA&quot;&gt;LaCie 8GB iamakey USB Flash Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B001V7XPSA&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mini Flashlight&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Business cards&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Moleskine San Francisco City Guide&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000JKN54E?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000JKN54E&quot;&gt;Moleskine Notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=hectorrcom-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B000JKN54E&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; - for note taking at the seminars&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;iPod Video&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pens and pencil&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;li&gt;Altoids&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please note that some of these links point to my Amazon Associates referral program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Exploring San Francisco&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4478.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Lonely Planet, makers of popular city exploring guides, has placed their&lt;a href=&quot;http://appshopper.com/travel/lonely-planet-san-francisco-city-guide&quot;&gt;San Francisco iPhone app on sale&lt;/a&gt;in anticipation of WWDC. The price is great: FREE. This, along with my Moleskine city guide and friend&amp;#8217;s recommendations, shall be enough to get me around San Francisco on those rare chances I might get to explore the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4478.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/IMG_4478.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EyeTour Puerto Rico Wins SME WebAd Award 2009</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/eyetour-puerto-rico-wins-sme-webad"/>
   <updated>2009-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/eyetour-puerto-rico-wins-sme-webad</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;width: 600px;&quot; src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/EyeTour-BestWebsite-SME-WebAdAward-Trophy.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1243392198381&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://eyetour.com/&quot;&gt;EyeTour.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Puerto Rico&amp;rsquo;s Premier Online Video Guide&lt;/em&gt;, won the 2009 WebAd Award for best website of the year, given by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smepr.org/&quot;&gt;Sales and Marketing Executives Association (SME) of Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;This online tourist guide to Puerto Rico, the first of its kind in the Caribbean, promotes the island as a world‐class destination through the Internet, taking advantage of the technological advances, interactivity, and global reach provided by the medium. The initiative, co‐founded by Juan Agust&amp;iacute;n M&amp;aacute;rquez, Jos&amp;eacute; Mart&amp;iacute;, and Alfredo Richner, began as a 40‐point tour of Old San Juan. EyeTour.com currently hosts over 100 videos of tourist attractions around the entire island, complemented by thousands of photographs and high‐quality editorial content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eyetour.com/&quot;&gt;EyeTour.com&lt;/a&gt; has become a unique online experience in the Caribbean, where visitors can explore Puerto Rico&amp;rsquo;s best attractions, including historical sites, beaches, nature reserves, museums, restaurants, and much more, through high‐quality videos, articles, and photographs. Visitors can download videos to their iPods, iPhone or personal video player of choice and realize our company&amp;rsquo;s vision: Be your own guide,&amp;rdquo; commented Jos&amp;eacute; Mart&amp;iacute;, President of Production for the company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are working on making &lt;a href=&quot;http://eyetour.com/&quot;&gt;EyeTour.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s unique audiovisual content available to the public through other means. A DVD series of Puerto Rico&amp;rsquo;s greatest attractions is in development, as well as a mobile application for the &lt;em&gt;iPhone&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;iPod touch&lt;/em&gt; that will take the tourist experience to a whole new level of interactivity,&amp;rdquo; mentioned Alfredo Richner, President of Research &amp;amp; Development for &lt;a href=&quot;http://eyetour.com/&quot;&gt;EyeTour.com&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;Also,&amp;rdquo; added Juan Agust&amp;iacute;n M&amp;aacute;rquez, President of Sales, &amp;ldquo;we are reaching out to the local business owners so they can advertise their services in the most innovative way possible &amp;ndash; through our online guide. We want every restaurant, tour operator, store, small and medium business, parador, and hotel in Puerto Rico to form part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://eyetour.com/&quot;&gt;EyeTour.com&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;By June 2009, &lt;a href=&quot;http://eyetour.com/&quot;&gt;EyeTour.com&lt;/a&gt; will have reached some 150,000 visitors from around the world with over half a million pages viewed this year. EyeTour.com launched on July 31, 2007 with the official support and sponsorship of the Puerto Rico Tourism Company. That same year it won the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enterprizepr.com&quot;&gt;EnterPRize Business Plan Competition&lt;/a&gt;, allowing the company to focus on the project&amp;rsquo;s expansion and development of a new, more robust, and agile website, which debuted December 2008 and was recently recognized as Best Website by the SME.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The WebAd Awards recognize the best use of the Internet in five categories: 1) best integration in a 360&amp;ordm; campaign, 2) best integration in a public relations or non‐profit campaign, 3) best integration in a promotional campaign, 4) best internet advertisement, and 5) best website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;full-image-block ssNonEditable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Foto EyeTour Team - WebAd Awards 2009.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1243392370373&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;thumbnail-caption&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px;&quot;&gt;The EyeTour Team accepts the award for Best Website.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The EyeTour production and web development team consists of Jos&amp;eacute; Mart&amp;iacute;, Juan Agust&amp;iacute;n M&amp;aacute;rquez, Alfredo Richner, Pablo L&amp;oacute;pez, Adri&amp;aacute;n Richner, Gabriel S&amp;aacute;nchez, Andr&amp;eacute;s Richner, Sherman Wildman, Danette Hudoba, Jacob Serlen, and Gerardo Rodriguez. Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Proper use of the iPhone touch keyboard</title>
   <link href="http://hectorramos.com/proper-use-of-iphone-touch-keyboard"/>
   <updated>2009-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://hectorramos.com/proper-use-of-iphone-touch-keyboard</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By far, the iPhone keyboard is the top reason given by my Puertorrican friends who have switched over to a Blackberry from an iPhone. I understand that this may be due mostly to our biling&amp;uuml;al nature, which is a problem when most of what we write every day is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanglish&quot; title=&quot;Spanglish&quot;&gt;mixture of english and spanish&lt;/a&gt;. Add to this the fact that most people are trying to touch type they same they would on a physical keyboard, and the result is utter frustration when it comes to typing on the small onscreen keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal bias aside, I find the iPhone keyboard to be almost perfect. I don&amp;#8217;t lose precious real estate on the surface of the phone to an always-there physical keyboard, nor do I have to carry a bulky sliding keyboard phone. In the following paragraphs I will try to cover this simple subject and maybe help others become one with their iPhone keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The International Keyboard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first trick to mastering the iPhone keyboard is to set up your language preferences. By specifying English and Spanish as your keyboard languages, you will be one step closer to quickly typing Spanglish sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you should access your Settings and navigate to General, then select Keyboard:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Picture%203.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3075809-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the bottom of the Keyboard screen. The International Keyboards screen will help you choose more than one keyboard to be used on any text entry across the iPhone OS. Toggle Spanish so that you have BOTH English and Spanish enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/storage%2FPicture%204.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3075836-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;International Keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/storage%2Fpost-images%2FPicture%206.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3076017-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing so will enable a small Globe icon whenever the keyboard pops up. This will be your new best friend when it comes to writing a mixture of English and Spanish on your iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/Picture%207.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://c185824.r24.cf1.rackcdn.com/3835484-3076032-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keyboard Select&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you hit this Globe icon, the keyboard layout will change between English, Spanish and any other keyboard you may have enabled (for fun, try the Japanese keyboards). Of course, you should choose either English or Spanish when you are writing mostly in just one of the languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when you are writing in spanglish, you will want to get used to hitting the globe to switch the language on the fly as you type. For example, you could be writing down a sentence in Spanish with the Spanish keyboard enabled, and your next word will be in English, you&amp;#8217;d hit the Globe before and after typing the English word. This will keep the auto-correct from matching your English word to the closest Spanish equivalent (now, it won&amp;#8217;t translate for you - what I mean by this is that it will find the cloest matching word according to the keystrokes - more on that next).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Auto-correction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going on, let me quickly go over how the iPhone&amp;#8217;s auto-correction works. The iPhone OS keeps track of all the keys you&amp;#8217;ve hit. If the word entered so far does not match a dictionary word, it will try to find the closest match by analyzing the keystrokes and all nearby keys. For example, if you were going to type &amp;#8220;cat&amp;#8221; but instead typed &amp;#8220;cst&amp;#8221;, the auto-correct may assume that you intended to hit the A key instead of the S key. It will offer the correction as a popup bubble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were to keep on typing, the auto-correct will engage and apply the suggested word. This may bother some, at first, but trust me, you will learn to love it. Your first few days you will have to get used to hitting the small &lt;strong&gt;x&lt;/strong&gt; in the bubble to reject the suggestion. The iPhone OS keeps track of these decisions in order to improve future suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, since the suggestion offered was &amp;#8220;cat&amp;#8221;, we would keep on typing our sentence, knowing that the iPhone has auto-corrected our typo without requiring extra effort on our part. This is the key to typing very fast on the iPhone - &lt;em&gt;train your auto-correction dictionary!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, this auto-correction feature may be a bother to those who only use one keyboard at a time. You are typing in spanglish and the dictionary will try to match your words to either English or Spanish, depending on your current preference. Now, if you get into the habit of switching the keyboard mid-sentence, you will quickly train both the English and Spanish keyboard into learning your spanglish dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t think about it!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last trick to quickly typing on the iPhone is to take all of this into account - and forget about it! Once you&amp;#8217;ve gotten used to both the English and Spanish keyboards, you should just start typing your words without looking at the keys. The auto-correction mechanism is quite good and it will start suggesting better matches for longer words. You may even type &amp;#8220;xirrextiom&amp;#8221; and find out that the OS will correctly suggest &amp;#8220;correction&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how I type. I just hit the general area of the key and let the OS do the rest. Keep practicing, and you will find yourself typing faster than any physical keyboard (on a mobile, that is) would allow you to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following video covers all the tips I&amp;#8217;ve mentioned throughout the article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=4622620&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=4622620&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/4622620&quot; title=&quot;Proper use of the iPhone multilingual keyboard&quot;&gt;Proper use of the iPhone multilingual keyboard&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user1000259&quot; title=&quot;hramos Vimeo profile&quot;&gt;H&amp;eacute;ctor Ramos&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot; title=&quot;Vimeo&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATED:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Originally, the video was uploaded to Flickr, which cut it off at 1:30. The Vimeo version has the whole video, where I go through the use of the multi-language Globe button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
 	
  <entry>
    <title>Netflix announces Latin American expansion</title>
    <link href="http://hectorramos.com/netflix-latin-america"/>
    <updated>2011-07-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hectorramos.com/netflix-latin-america</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5hsUJA2-B9pXzFOucJrZRnXpEvy9g?docId=CNG.bc84fe9157c6fc0692b67e0f94ba7a19.231&quot;&gt;Netflix to stream movies, TV shows to Latin America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Netflix did not say how much it plans to charge for the service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been streaming Netflix content all weekend long. Let's hope this doesn't mean that the $7.99 plan will cease to be in Puerto Rico (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/114196328607942287345&quot; title=&quot;Plus Profile&quot;&gt;Gabriel Pagan&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
    <title>JavaScriptCore apps</title>
    <link href="http://hectorramos.com/javascriptscore-apps"/>
    <updated>2011-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hectorramos.com/javascriptscore-apps</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoboslab.org/log/2011/04/ios-and-javascript-for-real-this-time&quot;&gt;iOS and JavaScript - for Real this Time!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So what's so special about these two games now? They don't use PhoneGap or Titanium. They don't even use a UIWebView. Instead, they bypass the iPhone's browser altogether and use Apple's JavaScript interpreter (JavaScriptCore) directly. All graphics are rendered with OpenGL instead of in a browser window and all sound and music is played back with OpenAL instead of… well, having no sound at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, this is a pretty cool trick.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
    <title>John Carmack on Android</title>
    <link href="http://hectorramos.com/carmack-on-android"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hectorramos.com/carmack-on-android</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nowgamer.com/print/feature/1308&quot;&gt;With Rage HD on iOS do you see yourself ever working on Android?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every six months I’d take a look at the scope of the Android, and decide if it was time to start really looking at it. At the last Quakecon I took a show of hands poll, and it was interesting to see how almost as many people there had an Android device as an iOS device. But when I asked how many peple had spent 20 bucks on a game in the Android store, there was a big difference. You’re just not making money in the Android space as you are in the iOS space.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We made more money than people may expect on the Doom RPG stuff. It’s just fun to develop on iOS. We’d show people what we were working on and they’d go “Oh, when are you going to ship that? And I’d say ‘next month’ and they’d go “Aww, I wanna work on an iPhone title.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s hard to make a rational business decision to say I want to take resources from something else and put them on this. We did actually hire a person to be our Android guy, but it looks like he’s going to get stuck on iOS development!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've &lt;a href=&quot;http://hectorramos.com/day-quake-shook-me-into-programming&quot;&gt;said it before&lt;/a&gt;, I got into programming thanks to John Carmack's work during the 90's.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
    <title>Slow Assimilation Works Best</title>
    <link href="http://hectorramos.com/slow-assimilation-works-best"/>
    <updated>2010-12-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hectorramos.com/slow-assimilation-works-best</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lots of cheering going on in Puerto Rico (I&amp;#8217;m part of the problem) but are getting enough &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamten.com/lawrence/writings/plan05.html&quot;&gt;done&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;People are quick to volunteer work and slow to work. The quickest way to kill a project is to attract people who will grind it to a halt with their enthusiastic non-action. Slow assimilation works best.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
    <title>The answer to "Will you mentor me?" is no</title>
    <link href="http://hectorramos.com/answer-to-you-mentor-me-is-no"/>
    <updated>2010-12-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hectorramos.com/answer-to-you-mentor-me-is-no</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pindancing.blogspot.com/2010/12/answer-to-will-you-mentor-me-is.html&quot;&gt;The answer to &amp;#8220;Will you mentor me?&amp;#8221; is no&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you claim to be &amp;#8220;very passionate about X&amp;#8221; but have never done anything concrete in X I find it difficult to take you seriously. People who are really passionate about anything don&amp;#8217;t wait for &amp;#8220;leaders&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;mentors&amp;#8221; before doing &lt;em&gt;concrete&lt;/em&gt; work in the area of their passion, however limited. Specifically wrt to programming/machine learning etc in the days of the internet and with sites like Amazon or the MIT OCW you have no limits except those you impose on yourself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For some reason Bangalore is crawling with people who first want to form a community and then start learning/working/whatever. These efforts almost invariably peter out uselessly. First do the work. Then if you feel like &amp;#8220;communing&amp;#8221; talk to others who are also working hard. Please read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamten.com/lawrence/writings/plan05.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, sent to me by my friend Prakash Swaminathan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sent my way by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/onedgepr&quot;&gt;Pablo&lt;/a&gt;, who says &amp;#8220;replace Bangalore with Puerto Rico.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
	
</feed>